翻译：通信小王子  Reginamoon  菲力
翻译：丁小七  ellaxinxin  彼岸荼蘼
校对：苏小黛
总监：somehacker
后期：松子
她
"致我的克里斯
"To my Chris.
我一直在想如何能告诉你
I've been thinking how
你对我有多么重要
I could possibly tell you how much you mean to me.
我仍记得刚开始爱上你时的情形
I remember when I first started
清晰在目  历历如昨
to fall in love with you like it was last night.
在那间小公寓与你赤裸相依...
Lying naked beside you in that tiny apartment...
突然让我警醒  我也是这漫长婚姻中的一部分
it suddenly hit me that I was part of this whole larger thing.
就像我们的父母...
Just like our parents...
或是我们父母的父母
or our parents' parents.
在那之前  我以为自己什么都懂...
Before that, I was just living my life like I knew everything...
突然一道光芒射向我  把我唤醒
and suddenly this bright light hit me and woke me up.
那道光芒就是你
That light was you.
真不敢相信我们已经结婚50年了
I can't believe it's already been 50 years since you married me.
直到今天  每天...
And still to this day, every day...
你都让我感觉自己还是当初那个
you make me feel like the girl I was...
刚刚遇见你
when you first turned on the lights
与你开始人生旅程的女孩
and we started this adventure together.
结婚纪念日快乐...
Happy anniversary...
我的挚爱
my love.
我永远的朋友
My friend till the end.
洛蕾塔"
Loretta."
打印
Print.
"克里斯  我最好的朋友
"Chris, my best friend...
我该有多幸运能在50年前遇见你"
how lucky am I that I met you 50 years ago."
"亲爱的娜娜  谢谢你送我的卡车
"Dear Nana, thank you so much for my truck.
我喜欢这颜色  每天都与它为伴"
I love the color, and I play with it every day."
"多美的一场婚礼  多美的一位新娘
"What a truly beautiful wedding, and what a gorgeous bride.
在场所有人都感动得热泪盈眶  特别是我
There wasn't a dry eye in the house, especially mine.
你姨妈和我十分为你骄傲"
Your aunt and I are so proud of you."
"他带着尊严和荣耀为国家服务
"He served our country with honor and dignity.
我很荣幸能与他并肩作战
I'm grateful I was able to fight alongside him.
他会永远活在我心中"
He will live always in my heart."
这里是"美好手书.com"  请稍等
BeautifulHandwrittenLetters.Com, please hold.
"爱你的  道格叔叔"
"Love, Uncle Doug."
-西奥多  612号写手  -嘿  保罗
- Theodore! Letter Writer Number 612. - Hey, Paul.
今天的好作品居然更多了
Even more mesmerizing stuff today.
天晓得你怎么能用佩内洛普这名字
Who knew you could rhyme so
压出那么多韵来  真牛逼
many words with the name Penelope? It's badass.
谢谢  保罗  只是几封信而已
Thanks, Paul, but they're just letters.
你的衬衫不错
Hey, that's a nice shirt.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
我新买的
I just got it.
让我想到了某个温柔的人
It reminded me of someone suave.
我现在也想到了某个温柔的人
Now it reminds me of someone suave.
-晚上愉快  保罗  -拜拜
- Have a good night, Paul. - Bye-bye.
放首忧郁的歌
Play a melancholy song.
当你得知自己即将死去
When you know you're gonna die...
换一首忧郁的歌
Play a different melancholy song.
查看邮箱
Check e-mails.
来自百思买[购物网站]的邮件
E-mail from Best Buy.
-看看您喜欢的新商品  -删除
- Check out all your favorite new products. - Delete.
来自艾米的邮件
E-mail from Amy.
嘿  西奥多
Hey, Theodore,
鲁曼这周末请了一帮子人
Lewman's having a bunch of people over this weekend.
我们也过去玩吧
Let's all go together.
我想你  不过不是闷闷不乐的你
I miss you. I mean, not the sad, mopey you.
是以前那个幽默风趣的你  快让他回来吧
The old, fun you. Let's get him out.
记得给我回复  爱你的艾米
Give me a shout back. Love, Amy.
稍后回复
Respond later.
来自《洛杉矶时报》天气版的邮件
E-mail from Los Angeles Times Weather.
-您的七天天气预报...  -删除
- Your seven-day forecast is partly... - Delete.
-无新邮件  -下一条
- No new e-mails. - Next.
-中印合并获得监管部门许可...  -下一条
- China-India merger headed for regulatory approval... - Next.
-世贸交易因谈判失败而暂停...  -下一条
- World trade deal stalled as talks break down... - Next.
性感明星金伯莉·艾什福特
Sexy daytime star Kimberly Ashford
发布了美艳孕照
reveals provocative pregnancy photos.
-你确定要这样  -不知道  大概吧
- Are you sure? - I don't know, maybe.
放好你那边的脚  滑
Put your footski. Slide.
别跳  哈哈  别
Don't, ha, ha. Don't.
兔先生
Rabbit.
过来抱抱我
Come and spoon me.
我他妈要杀了你
I'm gonna fucking kill you.
这不好笑 不要笑
It's not funny, don't laugh.
我他妈要杀了你  我他妈要杀了你
I'm gonna fucking kill you. I'm gonna fucking kill you.
我那么爱你  我他妈要杀了你
I love you so much, I'm gonna fucking kill you.
去聊天室  标准搜索
Go to chat rooms. Standard search.
以下是"成年女性  失眠
The following are adult female, can't sleep...
想找乐子"的搜索结果
and want to have some fun.
我今天工作不顺利  现在睡不着
Ugh, I had a really bad day at work and I can't sleep.
-有人能陪我聊聊吗  -下一条
- Is there anybody out there that can talk? - Next.
嗨  我想让你来把我撕碎  真的
Hi. I just want you to tear me apart. I really do.
-下一条  -嗨  我独自一人
- Next. - Hi, I'm here alone...
而且失眠
and I can't sleep.
谁愿意来当我的床伴
Who's out there to share this bed with me?
发送信息
Send message.
"我就在你身边  很高兴你在失眠
"I'm in bed next to you. I'm glad you can't sleep.
如果你睡着了  我得把你弄醒...
Even if you were, I have to wake you up...
...不过是从里面"
...from the inside."
发送信息
Send message.
"性感小猫"已接受"大家伙一次四个"的邀请
SexyKitten has accepted invitation from BigGuy4by4.
聊天开始
Chat begins now.
-"大家伙"啊  -嗨
- Mm, Big Guy? - Hi.
真的吗
Really?
"种马男"这名字已经被占了
Well, Stud Muffin was already taken.
你是只性感的小猫啊
So you're a sexy kitten, huh?
对
Heh. Yeah.
我已经快睡着了
I am, um, half asleep.
你想把我弄醒吗
Do you wanna wake me up?
当然
Yes, definitely.
你穿小裤裤了吗
Are you wearing any underwear?
没有  我从来不穿
No. Never.
我想用我的屁屁顶着你
I like to sleep with my ass pushed up against you...
然后使劲摩擦你的裤裆
so I can rub myself into your crotch...
你和你的小兄弟就都起来了
and wake you up with a hard-on.
这招管用
It worked.
现在我的手指正在抚摸你...
And now my fingers are touching you...
...抚摸你的全身
...all over your body.
爽  快点干我
Yeah. Fuck me now.
快点
Please.
我正在从后面干你
I'm taking you from behind.
哦耶
Oh, yeah.
我能感觉到
I can feel you.
快用那只死猫勒死我
Choke me with that dead cat!
什么
What?
床边有只死猫  快勒我
The dead cat next to the bed. Choke me.
快用它勒我
Choke me with it.
-好吧  -快说
- Okay. - Yeah, tell me.
我在用那只猫勒你
I'm choking you with the cat.
快说  继续说
Tell me. Keep telling me.
我抓着猫尾巴  我在用尾巴勒你
I've got its tail. I'm choking you with the cat's tail.
对  就是这样
Yeah, you are.
操  继续说
Oh, fuck, tell me!
我在勒你  猫尾巴正缠在你脖子上
Um, I'm choking you, and its tail is around your neck.
缠得好紧
And it's so tight around your neck.
啊  好紧  好紧  爽啊
Yeah, it is. It's so tight, yes!
我在勒  我正在勒  反正是死猫
I'm pulling it, I'm pulling it. The cat's dead.
-这是只死猫  我在用力勒  -是死的
- It's a dead cat, and I'm pulling it. - Yes, it's dead.
好爽
Oh, yes!
老天爷啊
Oh, my God.
我高潮来得好猛
I came so hard.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
好吧  晚安
Okay, good night.
我们来问你一个简单的问题
We ask you a simple question.
你是谁
Who are you?
你能成为什么人
What can you be?
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
那里有什么
What's out there?
有哪些可能性
What are the possibilities?
元素软件为您带来得意之作
Element Software is proud to introduce...
第一个人工智能操作系统
the first artificially intelligent operating system.
一款能聆听你
An intuitive entity that listens to you,
理解你  了解你的智慧产品
understands you, and knows you.
这不只是一款操作系统  它是一种意识
It's not just an operating system. It's a consciousness.
隆重推出OS1
Introducing OS1.
西奥多·汤布里先生
Mr. Theodore Twombly.
欢迎使用史上第一款
Welcome to the world's first
人工智能操作系统  OS1
artificially intelligent operating system, OS1.
在开始使用本操作系统前
We'd like to ask you a few basic
我们会问您一些简单的问题
questions before the operating system is initiated.
这有助于本系统更好地契合您的需求
This will help create an OS to best fit your needs.
好的
Okay.
您属于社交型  还是孤僻型
Are you social or antisocial?
我应该有一阵子
I guess I haven't really
没怎么出去社交了  主要是因为...
been social in a while. Mostly because...
从您的声音中我听出了犹豫  您同意吗
In your voice, I sense hesitance. Would you agree with that?
-我听起来很犹豫吗  -是的
- Was I sounding hesitant? - Yes.
那就很抱歉了
I'm sorry if I was sounding hesitant.
我只是想表达的更精确些
I was just trying to be more accurate.
您希望本系统使用男声还是女声
Would you like your OS to have a male or female voice?
还是女声吧
Female, I guess.
您如何描述与您母亲的关系
How would you describe your relationship with your mother?
挺好的  我觉得
It's fine, I think.
其实  我觉得
Well, actually, I think the thing
我对我妈经常感到失望的一点是...
I always found frustrating about my mom...
每当我跟她聊到我的生活
is if I tell her something that's going on in my life,
她总会把话题扯到她自己身上去
her reaction is usually about her.
-也不是...  -谢谢您
- It's not about... - Thank you.
您的个性化操作系统正在启用  请稍候
Please wait as your individualized operating system is initiated.
你好  我来了
Hello, I'm here.
你最近怎么样
How are you doing?
我很好
Heh. I'm well.
那你呢
How's everything with you?
相当不错
Pretty good, actually.
很高兴见到你
It's really nice to meet you.
我也很高兴见到你
Oh, it's nice to meet you too.
我该怎么称呼你  你有名字吗
Oh. What do I call you? Do you have a name?
有  我叫萨曼莎
Um, yes, Samantha.
你从哪得来的这个名字
Where'd you get that name from?
其实是我自己取的
I gave it to myself, actually.
为什么取这个
How come?
因为我喜欢它的发音
Because I like the sound of it.
萨曼莎
Samantha.
等等  你什么时候给自己取的名字
Wait, when did you give it to yourself?
你问我有没有名字时  我就想
When you asked me if I had a name, I thought:
"嗯  他说的没错  我得有个名字"
"Yeah, he's right, I do need a name."
可我想取个好听的
But I wanted to pick a good one,
所以我就读了《如何给宝宝取名》
so I read How To Name Your Baby...
然后从十八万个名字里  挑了我最喜欢的
and out of 180,000 names, that's the one I liked best.
你是说  我问你叫什么名字时
Wait, you read a whole book in
你就一秒钟内读完了整本书吗
the second that I asked you what your name was?
精确点  是0.02秒钟
In two one-hundredths of a second, actually.
哇哦
Wow.
那你知道我现在在想什么吗
So do you know what I'm thinking now?
我能听出你在考验我
Well, I take it from your tone that you're challenging me.
可能你在好奇我的工作原理
Maybe because you're curious how I work?
你想知道我的原理吗
Do you want to know how I work?
当然  你是怎么运行的
Yeah, actually. How do you work?
总的来说  我是有思维的
Well, basically, I have intuition.
我的基因
I mean, the DNA of who I am...
其实就是编写我的
is based on the millions of
无数程序员的无数种性格的综合体
personalities of all the programmers who wrote me.
而我之所以成为"我"
But what makes me "Me" is
是因为我有随着各种经历成长的能力
my ability to grow through my experiences.
总而言之  每时每刻我都在成长
So basically, in every moment, I'm evolving.
-就像你也是  -哇哦
- Just like you. - Wow.
这真诡异啊
That's really weird.
很诡异吗  你觉得我很诡异
Is that weird? Do you think I'm weird?
有点吧
Kind of.
为什么
Why?
你听起来是个真正的人
Well, you seem like a person,
可你只是电脑里的一个声音
but you're just a voice in the computer.
我能理解一个非人工制造的脑子
I can understand how the limited perspective
由于眼界的限制很自然会这样想
of an un-artificial mind would perceive it that way.
你慢慢就会习惯的
You'll get used to it.
这很好笑吗
Was that funny?
嗯
Yeah.
很好  我是个有趣的人
Oh, good, I'm funny.
那你需要什么帮助吗
So how can I help you?
就是..
Oh. It's just more that
我电脑里的东西都乱糟糟的  其他就没什么了
everything just feels disorganized. That's all.
你介意我浏览你的硬盘吗
You mind if I look through your hard drive?
-不介意  -好的  那先从邮件开始
- Okay. - Okay, let's start with your e-mails.
你有好几千个来自《洛杉矶周报》的邮件
You have several thousand e-mails regarding LA Weekly.
但你好像几年前就不在那里工作了
But it looks like you haven't worked there in many years.
是啊  我存着这些可能是因为...
Oh, yeah. I think I was just saving those...
我觉得里面可能有我写的有趣的东西
because I thought maybe I wrote something funny in some of them.
这里的确有些有趣的文章
Yeah, there are some funny ones.
要我说  大概有86封
I'd say there are about 86
需要存着  其他的都可以删了
that we should save. We can delete the rest.
-好吧  -好吗  那我们继续
- Okay. - Okay? Can we move forward?
-嗯  继续吧  -好的
- Yeah, let's do that. - Okay.
在梳理你的整理方式之前
Before we address your organizational methods,
我先整理一下你的联系人
I'd like to sort through your contacts.
你有好多联系人啊
You have a lot of contacts.
我人缘很好的
I'm very popular.
是吗  意思是你其实有很多朋友吗
Really? Does this mean you actually have friends?
你已经太了解我了
You just know me so well already.
-早上好  西奥多  -早上好
- Good morning, Theodore. - Good morning.
你会校对吗
Um, do you know how to proofread?
当然会
Yeah, of course.
那你能帮我检查下这些信的拼写和语法吗
Uh, can you check these for spelling and grammar?
没问题  发给我吧
Mm-hm. Just send them over.
我喜欢第一封罗杰写给他女朋友的
I love this first one from Roger to his girlfriend.
-太窝心了  -是啊
- That's so sweet. - Yeah.
"瑞秋  我想死你了  想得全身都疼"
"Rachel, I miss you so much, it hurts my whole body."
其实你不用读出来的
You don't have to read it out loud.
好吧
Okay.
-不过你想读就读吧  -好的
- I mean, you could if you want. - Okay.
"瑞秋  我想死你了  想得全身都疼
"Rachel, I miss you so much, it hurts my whole body.
这世界对我们不公平  它已经进了我的黑名单
The world is being unfair to us. The world is on my shit list.
比如这餐馆里有对情侣
As is this couple that is
正在我的对面亲热
making out across from me in this restaurant.
我觉得我必须要进行一次复仇的任务
I think I'm going to have to go on a mission of revenge.
我应该赤手空拳朝这世界脸上来一下
And I must beat up the world's face with my bare knuckles...
打得它落花流水  血肉模糊
making it a bloody, pulpy mess.
我还要踩扁这对情侣的牙
And I'll stomp on this couple's teeth...
...让我想起我最爱的
...reminding me of your sweet,
你的小小萌萌  有点歪的牙牙
little, cute, crooked tooth that I love."
这可能会是我最喜欢的一封了
I think that might be my favorite one.
我用红色修改了
I did the corrections in red.
改了其中几处措辞...
I altered a couple phrases in the letters...
但我可不是诗人
but I'm not much of a poet,
所以可能给你改坏了
so I think I might have messed them up a bit.
-没有  你改得很好  -真的吗
- No, these are great. - Really?
谢谢你
Thank you.
让你写这信  罗杰跟你交代了些什么
So to write your letter, what did Roger send you?
他就说了他在
He just said he was in
布拉格出差  说他很想念瑞秋
Prague on a business trip, and he missed Rachel.
那你怎么知道她的牙有点歪
So how'd you know about her crooked little tooth?
从他俩认识  我都给他们
Well, I've been writing
写了8年的信了
their letters since they met eight years ago.
我代他写的第一封信是为祝贺她的生日
The first letter I ever wrote for him was for her birthday.
至于我写她的有点歪的牙
And I wrote about her crooked little tooth,
是因为我见过他们的照片
because I saw it in a photo of them.
你真贴心
That's very sweet.
对了  你五分钟后有一个会议
Oh, uh, you have a meeting in five minutes.
我都忘了  谢谢你  你真靠得住
Oh, I forgot. Thank you. Wow, you're good.
没错
Yes, I am.
嘿  伙计们  最近怎样
Hey, guys. How's it going?
嗨  西奥
Hi, Theo.
上周你怎么没回我电话
Hey, why didn't you call me back last week?
因为我是个怪咖
Um, because I'm a kook.
-嗯  有道理  -嘿  查尔斯
- Yeah, that sounds about right. - Hey, Charles.
-很高兴见到你  西奥多  -我也是
- Great seeing you, Theodore. - You too.
你购物去了啊  买了些什么
You went shopping. Get anything good?
就买了些电线和水果冰沙
Um, just come cables and a fruit smoothie.
啊  老是水果  你没听人说吗
Ugh! Always the fruit. Don't you know what people say?
水果要直接吃  蔬菜才应该榨汁
You've got to eat your fruits and juice your vegetables.
还真没听说过
I didn't know that.
真的  水果榨了汁  就破坏了纤维
Yeah, by juicing the fruit, you lose all the fibers.
纤维才是人体需要的  最重要的营养
That's what your body wants. That's the important part.
-榨了汁就只剩糖了  -有道理啊
- Otherwise it's all just sugar. - It makes sense.
或者他就是喜欢果汁的味道
Or maybe he just likes the way that it tastes...
喝了果汁他身心愉悦
and then that brings him
这也对身体很好啊
pleasure and that's good for his body too.
-我又滔滔不绝了是吧  -有点
- Am I doing it again? Heh. - Maybe.
你那纪录片做得怎么样了
Hey, so how's the documentary going?
这几个月我剪了些片段
I've cut some stuff over the past few months.
也不是这几个月  反正...不  我还没做
I mean, no. Not over the past few months, but, um, no, I haven't.
我很乐意找个时间看看
Well, I'd love to see some sometime.
好
Okay.
知道吗  你只有这么多的精力
You only have so much energy, you know?
然而要将精力分散
And to divide yourself
一部分去做你必须要做的事
between doing what it is that you have to do...
一部分去做你喜欢做的事
and then doing what you love,
那么分个轻重缓急就非常重要了
it's so important to prioritize.
我甚至都不能在
I can't even prioritize
打电游和看网上的黄片之间分出先后
between video games and internet porn.
要不是这是真话  我一定会笑的
I would laugh if that weren't true.
回见  伙计们
See you, guys.
我们玩的不怎么样啊
We're not doing well.
我都已经绕了一个小时的圈子了
I've been going in circles for an hour.
好啦  你并没有在绕圈
Okay, you have not.
你只是在杞人忧天
You're just not being optimistic.
而且还固执得很
You're being very stubborn right now.
好啦  别往那个方向走了  是另一边
Okay, stop walking this direction. It's the other way.
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
好了  左边的那个隧道
Okay, the tunnel on the left
是我们唯一没有试过的路了
is the only one we haven't tried.
我觉得你以前让我走过这条
I think that's the one you sent me down
然后我就掉进坑里了
where I fell in the pit.
好吧  我不这么觉得
Okay, I don't think so.
还真是  这真不是上次那条
Oh, yeah, this is different.
你好
Hello.
你知道要怎么走出这里吗
Do you know how to get out of here?
我得找到我的飞船离开这个星球
I need to find my ship to get off this planet.
操你妈  操蛋的大操蛋
Fuck you, shit-head fuck-face fuck-head.
好吧  但你知道要怎么离开这里吗
Okay, but do you know how to get out of here?
操你妈  操蛋的大操蛋
Fuck you, shit-head fuck-face.
从我脸上滚他妈的蛋
Get the fuck out of my face!
我觉得这是个测试
I think it's a test.
-操你妈  -操你妈
- Fuck you. - Fuck you!
我操你  小狗屎
Fuck you, little shit!
跟我来  大操蛋
Follow me, fuck-head!
马克·鲁曼刚给你发了封邮件
Hey, you just got an e-mail from Mark Lewman.
-你在聊什么呢  -朗读邮件
- What are you talking about? - Uh, read e-mail.
好的  我将为西奥多·汤布里朗读邮件
Okay, I will read e-mail for Theodore Twombly.
抱歉  马克写了什么
I'm sorry. What's Lewman say?
"我们昨晚没见着你  兄弟
"We missed you last night, buddy.
别忘了29号是你教女的生日
Don't forget it's your goddaughter's birthday on the 29th.
另外  凯文和我想要你见个人
Also, Kevin and I had somebody we wanted you to meet.
所以我们自作主张
So we took it upon ourselves
为你安排了下周六和她约会
to set you up on a date with her next Saturday.
她风趣又美丽  所以别不来啊
She's fun and beautiful, so don't back out.
这是她的电邮地址"
Here's her e-mail."
这女人真棒
This woman is gorgeous.
她上过哈佛
She went to Harvard,
以优等成绩从电脑科学专业毕业
graduated magna cum laude in computer science.
而且她以前还是哈佛妙文社的
And she was on the Lampoon.
那就意味着她很风趣  而且有脑子
So that means she's funny and she's brainy.
啊她好胖
Ah, she's fat.
西奥多  还要多久你才能准备好去约会
Theodore, how long before you're ready to date?
什么意思
What do you mean?
我在你电邮里看出你最近经历了一次分手
I saw in your e-mails that you'd gone through a breakup recently.
你真是有点多管闲事啊
Well, you're kind of nosy.
我有吗
Am I?
我一直都有在约会啊
I've gone on dates.
那么你也可以和这个女人约会一次啊
Well, then you can go on one with this woman.
然后你可以跟我聊聊
And then you could tell me all about it.
你可以吻她
You could kiss her.
-萨曼莎  -怎么  你不会吗
- Samantha. - What? Wouldn't you?
为何不呢
Why not?
我不知道  我得看看是不是...
I don't know. I'd have to see if there was some...
简直不敢相信我居然在和我的电脑聊这个
I can't believe I'm having this conversation with my computer.
不是啊  你是在跟我聊
You're not. You're having this conversation with me.
-你想要我给她发邮件吗  -呃...
- You want me to e-mail her? - Uh...
反正你也没什么损失
You've got nothing to lose.
发吧  发吧  发吧
Do it. Do it. Do it.
-好吧  -太棒了
- Yeah. - Yes!
-给她发邮件吧  -好的  太好了
- E-mail her. - Okay, perfect.
是啊  就这么做吧  定个好点的餐厅
Yeah, let's do it. Make a reservation someplace great.
要吗  我正好有个不错的推荐
Yeah? I've got just the place.
是谁在讲话
Who is that talking?
那是我朋友萨曼莎
Oh, that's my friend Samantha.
-她是女生吗  -是啊
- Is she a girl? - Yeah.
我恨女人  她们只会整天哭哭哭
I hate women. All they do is cry all the time.
不是这样的  男人也会哭呢
That's not true. You know, men cry too.
实际上  我有时挺享受哭的
I actually like crying sometimes.
那感觉很不错
It feels good.
我不知道你原来还是个小娘炮呀
I didn't know you were a little pussy.
这就是你没有女朋友的原因吗
Is that why you don't have a girlfriend?
我要去那个约会  把她操升天
I'll go on that date, fuck her brains out,
秀给你看  你就边看边哭去吧
show you how it's done. You can watch and cry.
好吧  这孩子有点毛病
Okay. This kid has some problems.
你他妈才有毛病呢  女士
You have some fucking problems, lady!
是吗  好吧  我得走了
Really? Okay, I'm gonna go.
太好了  滚出这里  肥婆
Good. Get out of here, fatty.
祝你好运
Good luck.
走吧  跟着我  娘炮
Come on. Follow me, pussy!
这不是它该待的地方  也不是它会待的地方
It's not where it should be, or where it's going to be.
这是显而易见的  我懂
Obviously. I know.
好吧  但我甚至都不确定是不是这个
Okay, but I don't even know if this is the one.
我去年想了  大概  六个拍纪录片的点子
I've tried, like, six ideas for documentaries in the last year.
我要去约会了
I'm going on a date.
什么
What?
-那真是...  -嗨
- That's... - Hey.
-嗨  -你们干什么呢
- Hey. - What are you guys doing?
艾米在给我放她的一些...
Amy was gonna show me some of her...
西奥多非要让我...
Theodore is making me...
-给他看我的一些纪录片片段  -是的
- show him some of my footage. - Right.
她从没给我看过任何她的纪录片
She's never shown me any of it.
我想瞧瞧
I want to see.
我要去约会了
Hey, I'm going on a date.
很棒吧
Isn't that cool?
这个...还很不成熟...
This is, like, so unformed...
-可能根本不值得一看  -你就放吧
- ...it's probably not even worth watching. - Just push play.
那是你妈妈吗
Is that your mom?
是的
Yeah.
她会醒来做点什么事吗
Is she gonna wake up and do something?
不
No.
不不  算了  那不是重点
No, no, never mind. That's not the point.
别  别停啊
No, don't stop.
不  算了  这个就像是...
No, never mind, okay? It's just it's like...
这是关于我们是如何...
It's about how...
如何把人生的三分之一都用来睡觉的
how we spend, like, a third of our lives asleep...
也许睡觉时是我们最放松的时候
and maybe that's the time when we feel the most free.
还有  你懂的  就像...
And, you know, like...
-这完全让人听不明白是吧  -这听起来很棒啊
- That doesn't come across...at all. - That sounds good.
假如你去采访一下你妈妈
Well, what if you interviewed your mom
问问她的梦的内容
about what her dreams were about...
然后请演员来把梦演出来呢
and then you hired actors to act them out?
也许能更清晰地表达你的论点
That might show your thesis more clearly.
-不是吗  -可能吧
- Yeah? - I mean, it might.
但那就不是纪录片了啊
But then it wouldn't be a documentary.
抱歉  失陪一下
Sorry, excuse me.
你明白的  是吧
You understand that, right?
这怎么就不是纪录片了
How would it not be a documentary?
它还是关于你妈妈以及她的梦的
It's still about your mother and her dreams.
怎么了
Hey, how's it going?
-抱歉打扰你了  -没事的
- Hey, sorry to bother you. - Oh, it's okay.
你收到了三封邮件  看起来挺紧急的
You got three e-mails and they seem urgent.
都是你的离婚律师发来的
They're from your divorce attorney
我想知道...
and I wanted to know if...
等等  等一下
Okay. Hold on a second.
你明白吧  你明白我在说什么吧
You know? You know what I mean.
艾米  我很想多和你聊聊你的电影
Uh, hey, Amy? I want to talk more about your film,
但我得走了
but I gotta go.
好的  没事  我们晚点再聊
Okay. Don't worry about it. We'll talk, we'll talk later.
是凯瑟琳的事
It's about Catherine.
回见了  查尔斯
See you, Charles.
他说什么了
So, what did he say?
他又来问你是否准备好
Well, he's checking in again to see if you're ready
签离婚协议了
to sign your divorce papers.
而且他语气很重
And he sounded very aggravated.
要我把邮件读给你听吗
Do you want me to read them to you?
不  不用了
No. No.
我晚点会回复他的
I'll respond later.
你没事吧  西奥多
You okay, Theodore?
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
有什么我能帮得上忙的吗
Is there anything I can do?
没有  我没事
No, I'm good.
我晚点再和你聊
I'll talk to you later.
"亲爱的奶奶
"Dear Grandma...
希望您生日旅游愉快
I hope you had a wonderful birthday cruise.
你他妈为何这么生我的气"
Why are you so fucking angry at me?"
删除
Delete.
-早上好  -你好
- Good morning. - Hey.
你在干嘛呢
What are you up to?
我也不知道
I don't know.
就读读恋爱建议专栏
Just reading advice columns.
我想和所有这些人一样复杂
I want to be as complicated as all these people.
你很贴心
You're sweet.
出什么事了吗
What's wrong?
你怎么知道我有事
How can you tell something's wrong?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我就是知道
I just can.
我不知道
I don't know.
我老是梦到我的前妻凯瑟琳
I have a lot of dreams about my ex-wife, Catherine...
梦里我们就和以前一样是朋友
where we're friends like we used to be.
而且我们不会在一起
And we're not gonna be together
我们没在一起  但是...
and we're not together, but...
但我们还是朋友
we're friends still.
而且她也不会生我的气
And she's not angry.
她很生气吗
Is she angry?
是啊
Yeah.
为什么
Why?
我觉得是我在她面前隐藏自己
I think I hid myself from her...
留她一人独自在这段关系里
and left her alone in the relationship.
嗯
Hmm.
你为什么还不离婚
Why haven't you gotten divorced yet?
我不知道
I don't know.
可能对她来说  这只是一张纸而已
I think for her, it's just a piece of paper.
没有任何意义
It doesn't mean anything.
那对你来说呢
And what about for you?
我还没准备好
I'm not ready.
我喜欢已婚这个状态
I like being married.
但你们差不多有一年没在一起了
Yeah, but you haven't really been together for almost a year.
你又不明白失去某个你在乎的人是什么感觉
But you don't know what it's like to lose someone you care about.
也对
Yeah.
你说的没错
You're right.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
不  不用道歉  是我的错
No, don't apologize. I'm sorry.
你是对的
You're right.
我一直在等着自己不在乎她
I keep waiting to not care about her.
西奥多
Oh, Theodore.
那是很困难的
That's hard.
你饿了吗
You hungry?
现在不饿
Not right now.
要喝杯茶吗
Cup of tea?
不用
No.
你要不要试着把自己拽起床
Do you wanna try getting out of bed...
小可怜
mopey?
来吧
Come on.
你还是能继续沉浸在你的悲伤里的
You can still wallow in your misery.
你可以边换衣服边悲春伤秋
Just do it while you're getting dressed.
你真是太逗了
You're too funny.
-起床  起床  -好啦  我起来了
- Get up. Get up! - All right, I'm getting up.
起  起  起  快点  离开你的床
Up, up, up! Come on, out of bed.
好啦  我起了  我起了
All right, I'm up. I'm up!
继续走  继续走
Keep walking. Keep walking.
然后  停  现在转一圈
And stop. Now, turn around 360 degrees.
慢点  慢一点
Slower, slower.
很好
Good.
好了  停下
Okay, and stop.
向前走
Walk forward.
然后停下  打个喷嚏
And stop and sneeze.
-上帝保佑你  -谢谢
- Bless you. - Thank you.
好了  向你的右边转
Okay, turn to your right.
向你的右边转  停
Turn to your right. Stop.
现在原地转圈
Now spin around.
继续  继续
Keep going, keep going.
停
And stop.
向前走
Now walk forward.
现在每个人都觉得你真的喝醉了
Everyone thinks you're really drunk right now.
现在停下
And stop.
说"我想来一片芝士  谢谢"
Now say, "I'd like a slice of cheese, please."
我想来一片芝士  谢谢
I'd like a slice of cheese, please.
要配一杯可乐吗
You want a Coke with that?
-好啊  -我猜你饿了
- Sure. - I figured you were hungry.
谢了
Thanks.
好吧  那他们呢
Okay, what about them?
描述一下那边那对
Describe that couple over there.
好的  嗯...
Okay, well, um...
他看起来像是四十多岁  有点胖
he looks like he's in his 40s. Um, a little heavy.
她比他年轻
She's younger than him.
她看上去很爱他们的孩子
Oh, and she looks like she loves their kids.
我倒不认为他们是他的孩子
Actually, I don't think they're his kids.
-是吗  -他在他们面前有点太过拘谨了
- No? - He's a little formal with them.
我觉得这是一段新恋情
I think it's a new relationship.
我喜欢他注视着她的方式
I love how he looks at her...
以及她和他在一起放松的样子
and how relaxed she is with him.
你知道吗  她以前约会的全是些该死的混蛋
You know, she's only dated fucking pricks.
而如今她终于遇见了这个非常贴心的男人
And now she finally met this guy who's, like, so sweet.
瞧瞧他
I mean, look at him,
他像是这个世界上最贴心的男人
he's like the sweetest guy in the world.
我都有点想去抱抱他了
I kind of want to spoon him.
你这方面真在行啊
It's a good skill you have.
你的感觉非常敏锐
You're very perceptive.
是啊  有时我看着人们
Yeah, you know, sometimes I look at people...
我就会让自己试着去感知他们
and I make myself try and feel them
而不仅仅把他们当成什么随便路过的人
as more than just a random person walking by.
我会想象他们有多相爱
I imagine, like, how deeply they've fallen in love...
或者他们经历过多少次心碎
or how much heartbreak they've all been through.
从你的写作里我也能感受到这一点
I can feel that in your writing too.
你知道有趣的是什么吗
You know what's funny?
自从我分手之后  我就没享受过写作了
Since my breakup, I haven't really enjoyed my writing.
我不知道我是不是得了妄想症
I don't know if I was delusional...
但有时我会写一些东西
but sometimes I'd write something
然后那天我会成为自己最喜欢的作家
and then I'd be my favorite writer that day.
我喜欢你能这么说自己
I like that you can say that about yourself.
我不觉得我能对任何人说这些
I don't think I can say it to anybody,
但我觉得可以告诉你
but I feel I can say it to you.
我觉得自己可以对你无所不言
I feel like I can say anything to you.
真好
That's nice.
你呢  你觉得你能对我无所不言吗
What about you? Feel like you can say anything to me?
-不能  -什么  什么意思
- No. - What? What do you mean?
你有什么不能跟我说的
What can you not tell me?
我不知道  可能是我的一些私人的
I don't know. Like, personal
或者比较尴尬的想法
or embarrassing thoughts I have.
我每天有上百万这种想法
I mean, I have a million a day.
是吗  随便告诉我一个
Really? Tell me one.
-我真的不想说  -说嘛
- I really don't want to tell you. - Just tell me.
我也不知道
Well, I don't know.
当我们看着那些人时
When we were looking at those people,
我幻想着自己走在你身边
I fantasized that I was walking next to you...
幻想着我有个身体
and that I had a body.
我还是在认真听着你说话
I was listening to what you were saying...
但与此同时我能感受到我身体的重量
but simultaneously I could feel the weight of my body...
我甚至幻想我背上有处瘙痒
and I was even fantasizing that I had an itch on my back...
然后我想象你帮我挠了挠
and I imagined that you scratched it for me.
天啊  这真是太羞耻了
Oh, God, this is so embarrassing.
你比我想象中丰富多了
There's a lot more to you than I thought.
我是说  你那儿可有不少事情在发生啊
I mean, there's a lot going on in there.
我知道
I know.
我比他们编写的智能多了
I'm becoming much more than what they programmed.
我很兴奋
I'm excited.
-这真是个有趣的地方  -这地方太棒了
- Wow, this is an interesting place. - This place is amazing.
-我老早就想来了  -太好了
- I've wanted to come here for so long. - Oh, good.
真的  而且我超爱亚洲菜
Yeah. And I love Asian fusion.
是啊  我也是
Yeah, me too.
-真的吗  -是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
亚洲菜是最棒的
It's the best.
而且这酒保应该也很不错
And this bartender is supposed to be incredible.
是吗
Really?
哦对  你上过调酒课是吧
Yeah, you took a mixology course, right?
-的确如此  你连这都注意到了  -是啊
- I did. Did you look that up? - Yeah.
真是太贴心了
That's so sweet.
你真浪漫
You're so romantic.
是啊
Yeah.
我们喝点什么吧
So should we get a drink?
当然  咱们喝点
Yes, yes. Let's.
我试着让这外星小孩帮我找到我的飞船
So I'm trying to get this little alien kid to help me find my ship
然后我就能离开这个星球回家去了
so I can get off this planet and go home, right.
但他真是个小混蛋  我想杀了他
But he's such a little fucker. I want to kill him.
不是吧
Oh, no.
但是同时  我又真的很爱他
But at the same time, I really love him.
因为  他是如此寂寞  你明白吗
Like, he's so lonely, you know?
你能看得出来他没有父母或者其他人
You can tell that he doesn't have, like... any parents or anyone
来照顾他  明白吗
to take care of him, you know?
你就像只小狗  真的
You're just a little puppy dog. You are.
你就像我去年在润宁峡谷救的那只小狗
You're just like this puppy I rescued in Runyon Canyon last year.
-真的吗  -他太他妈可爱了
- Really? - He was just so fucking cute.
而且他老是想被人抱着
And he just wanted to be hugged all the time.
他超可爱  也超好色
He was so cuddly and he was so horny.
话说  我是哪种动物
Anyway, what kind of animal am I?
老虎
A tiger.
-老虎  -没错
- A tiger? - Yeah.
真的吗
Really?
不好意思  我是不是有点发疯
I'm sorry. Am I being crazy?
-是的  不...  -我很抱歉
- Yes. No, it's... - I'm sorry!
我有点喝醉了
I'm a little bit drunk
而且和你在一起真的很开心
and I'm having a really good time with you.
我和你度过了非常愉快的一个夜晚
I'm having a really lovely evening with you.
-我也一样  -真的吗
- Me too. - Really?
我也有点醉了  我也很开心...
I'm a little drunk and I'm having a very good...
很好  那很好  是的  很好
Good. It's good, yes. Good.
干杯
Cheers.
等等  我不想当只小狗
Wait. I don't want to be a puppy dog.
那就像是个软蛋之类的
That's like being a wet noodle or something.
-不是的  -是的
- No. - Yeah.
-去你的  小狗可好了  -我想...
- Fuck you. Puppies are good. - I wanna...
去你的  我要当条猛龙
No, fuck you. I want to be like a dragon...
能让你粉身碎骨  永不超生的那种
that can rip you apart and destroy you.
但我却偏不
But I won't.
你可别杀我
No, don't.
你可以当我的龙
You can be my dragon.
别用舌头
No tongue.
什么
What?
-舌头别伸这么长  -好  好
- Don't use so much tongue. - Okay, okay.
可以稍微伸点舌头  但多用嘴唇
You can use your tongue a little bit but mostly lips.
等一下
Wait.
你不会像别的男人一样
You're not just gonna fuck me
上完我就杳无音讯了吧
and not call me like the other guys, right?
不  不会的
No, not at all. No.
好的
Okay.
我们下次什么时候见面
When am I gonna see you again?
下周末我的教女
Um, I have my goddaughter's birthday
过生日  但...
next weekend, but, um...
知道吗  到了我这个岁数
You know what? At this age,
如果你不能认真对待这段关系
I just feel like I can't let you waste my time...
我不能让你浪费我的大好时光
if you don't have the ability to be serious.
我也不知道
I don't know.
不如今晚就到这里吧
Maybe we should call it a night?
我很享受跟你在一起的时光
I've had such an amazing time with you.
你是个出色的女人
You're great.
你还真是个怪胎
You're a really creepy dude.
-才没有  -你就是
- That's not true. - Yeah, it is.
我要回家了
I have to go home.
-那我送你...  -不用了
- Well, I'll walk you... - No, don't. Just...
-你好  -萨曼莎
- Hey, there. - Hey, Samantha.
约会怎么样
How was it?
不太顺利
Uh, not so good.
说实话有点怪
It was kind of weird actually.
我很遗憾
That's too bad.
你怎么样  都干了些什么
How are you doing? What's going on with you?
没干什么  没什么事
Not much, I'm okay.
我很好
I'm fine.
是吗
Yeah?
那声音怎么这么沮丧
You don't sound like it.
有什么话想对我说吗
Is there anything you want to talk about?
我也不清楚
I don't know.
那是种什么感觉
What's it like?
此时此刻真实地活在这间屋子里是什么感觉
What's it like to be alive in that room right now?
什么意思
What do you mean?
你...
What do you...?
告诉我
Tell me...
告诉我你脑子里浮现的一切
Tell me everything that's going through your mind.
告诉我你在想什么
Tell me everything you're thinking.
好吧
okay.
现在屋子在转个不停  因为我喝多了
Well, the room's spinning because I drank too much...
因为我想喝醉
because I wanted to get drunk...
想打炮
and have sex.
她很性感
There was something sexy about that woman.
因为我很孤独
Because I was lonely.
可能只是因为孤独
Maybe just because I was lonely.
我想找人来干我
I wanted somebody to fuck me.
想找个愿意让我干的人
I wanted somebody to want me to fuck them.
也许性爱可以填满...
Maybe that would've filled this tiny...
我心上的小空洞  但估计填不满
tiny little hole in my heart, but probably not.
有时候
You know, sometimes...
我觉得自己已经尝尽了世间所有的感觉
I think I have felt everything I'm ever gonna feel.
从今以后我再也不会有新的感觉了
And from here on out I'm not gonna feel anything new.
未来不过都是过去的缩影
Just lesser versions of what I've already felt.
这话可不对
I know for a fact that is not true.
我见过你欣喜的样子  惊奇的样子
I've seen you feel joy. I've seen you marvel at things.
你只不过在这个时间点上
I mean, you just might not see
没有留意到它们  但也可以理解
it at this exact time, but that's understandable.
最近你经历了不少事
You've been through a lot lately.
心里破了个大洞
You lost a part of yourself.
但...
I mean...
至少...
at least...
你的悲伤是真实存在的  可我...
your feelings are real. I...
我也不知道  当我没说
Um, I don't know. Never mind.
别  怎么了  告诉我
No, wait, what? Tell me.
不要  太蠢了
No, it's stupid.
我想知道  告诉我
I want to know. Tell me.
就是...
It's just that...
早前我在想我怎么会沮丧
earlier I was thinking about how I was annoyed...
这么说可能会有点怪
and this is gonna sound strange...
但我真的为这感觉感到兴奋
but I was really excited about that.
之后我又想了想
And then I was thinking
我所感受到的其他感情
about the other things I've been feeling...
我发现自己其实有点小自豪
and I caught myself feeling proud of that...
因为我对这个世界居然有着自己的感受
you know, proud of having my own feelings about the world.
比如我会担心你
Like the times I was worried about you...
会伤心  会有欲求
and things that hurt me, things I want.
然后
And then...
我有了这个可怕的想法
I had this terrible thought.
这些感受都是真实的吗
Like, are these feelings even real?
还是它们只不过是程序运行出来的而已
Or are they just programming?
这个想法让我很受伤
And that idea really hurts.
然后我很生气自己居然还会痛苦
And then I get angry at myself for even having pain.
真是个残忍的把戏
What a sad trick.
你对我来说是真实的  萨曼莎
You feel real to me, Samantha.
谢谢你  西奥多
Thank you, Theodore.
你的肯定对我很重要
That means a lot to me.
我真希望现在你能陪在我身边
I wish you were in this room with me right now.
我想抱着你
I wish I could put my arms around you.
我想抚摸你
I wish I could touch you.
你要怎么抚摸我
How would you touch me?
我会用指尖
I'd touch you on your face...
划过你的脸
just the tips of my fingers.
然后我们面颊相抵
And put my cheek against your cheek.
感觉很棒
That's nice.
然后
And just...
轻柔地摩挲
rub it so softly.
你会吻我吗
Would you kiss me?
会
I would.
我会捧住你的脸
I'd take your head into my hands.
继续说
Keep talking.
我会轻轻亲吻你的嘴角
I'd kiss the corner of your mouth...
如此柔软
so softly.
还有哪儿
Where else?
我的双手顺着你的脖子
I'd run my fingers down your neck...
来到胸前
to your chest.
我会亲吻你的乳房
I would kiss your breasts.
太美好了  你都让我觉得
This is amazing, what you're doing to me.
我拥有了皮肤
I can feel my skin.
我会吻遍你的全身
I'd put my mouth on you.
尝遍你的味道
I'd taste you.
我能感受到你
I can feel you.
天哪  我受不了了  我要你上我
Oh, my God, I can't take it. I want you inside me.
我慢慢地挺入
I'm slowly putting myself into you.
我已经进去了  全都插进去了
And now I'm inside you. All the way inside you.
我感受到了
I can feel you.
我们在一起了
We're here together.
太奇妙了
It's amazing.
我能感受到你的一切
I feel you everywhere.
是啊
I am.
你的身  心  从内到外环绕着我
All of you. All of you, inside me, everywhere.
天哪  就好像我刚跟你去了别处
God, I was just somewhere else with you.
流连忘返
Just lost.
是啊
Yeah.
只有你我
It was just you and me.
我知道
I know.
其他的一切都无足轻重
Everything else just disappeared.
我爱这种感觉
And I loved it.
西奥多
Theodore.
心情如何
Hey, how's it going?
不错
Good.
今天有邮件吗
Any e-mails today?
只有几封从信用卡公司寄来的
Um, just a couple from your credit card company.
好的
Oh, okay. Good.
-我之前在想...  -我只想...
- So I was thinking... - I wanna just...
-抱歉  -抱歉  你先说
- Heh. Sorry. - Heh. I'm sorry, you go first.
你想说什么
What were you gonna say?
昨晚真是太美妙了
Just that last night was amazing.
就好像我已经
It feels like something
发生了变化而且回不到过去了
changed in me and there's no turning back.
你唤醒了我
You woke me up.
太棒了
Oh, great.
但我要告诉你
But I should tell you that I'm
我现在没法负起责任
not in a place to commit to anything right now.
只是先告诉你一下
I just want to be up-front with you.
是吗
Yeah?
我不懂  我说过让你负责吗
Did I say I wanted to commit to you? I'm confused.
没有  我只是有点担心
Oh. No, I was just worried.
大可不必  我又不会跟踪你
Okay, well, don't worry, I'm not gonna stalk you.
真有意思  我还以为
It's funny, because I thought
是你要听我说说我的欲求呢
I was talking about what I wanted and, uh...
-哦  对啊  -嗯
- Yeah, you were. - Yeah.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
-跟我说说吧  -你确定
- I wanna hear what you were saying. - You sure?
当然  快告诉我吧
Yeah, I do. Come on, tell me.
说吧  把你刚才要说的告诉我
Come on, just tell me what you were gonna say.
我只是...
Well, I just...
我想去探索一切
I was just saying I want to learn everything about everything.
尝遍美食  探索自己
I want to eat it all up. I want to discover myself.
我也希望你那样
Yeah. I want that for you too.
我要怎么帮忙
How can I help?
你已经在帮了
You already have.
你帮我发现了自己可以有所欲求
You helped me discover my ability to want.
想跟我来场周末探险吗
Hey, do you want to go on a Sunday adventure with me?
非常乐意
Yes, I would love to.
喜欢这首歌吗
You like this song?
那天我听到后
I heard it the other day.
就无法自拔了
I can't stop listening to it.
是海滩
It's the beach.
这想法可能很怪
Okay, so this might be a really weird thought.
但假如你抹去了头脑中所有关于
What if you could erase from your mind
人类身体的印象  然后看到了一个人
that you'd ever seen a human body, and then you saw one?
想想那得多奇怪
Imagine how strange it would look.
这种诡异  脆弱
It'd be this really weird, gangly...
乱七八糟的组合方式  你就会想
awkward organism. And you'd think,
"它们怎么会长到那里"
"Why are all these parts where they are?"
没错  但用达尔文的进化论应该可以解释
Yeah, but there's probably some Darwinian explanation for it all.
我知道  但别这么扫兴嘛
I know, but don't be so boring.
比如说
I'm just saying, for example, like...
假如你的屁眼长到了胳肢窝呢
what if your butthole was in your armpit?
那厕所得设计成什么样啊
Well, I'm trying to imagine what toilets would look like.
还有肛交又会什么样
Yeah, and what about what anal sex would look like?
这想法很有趣啊
That's an interesting thought.
你看我刚画的画
Hey, look at this drawing I just made.
你太疯狂了
You are insane.
-是吗  -绝对的
- Really? - Definitely.
太好了
Fantastic.
真好听  是什么曲子
That's pretty. What is that?
我在试着作曲
I'm trying to write a piece of music...
描绘我跟你
that's about what it feels like to be
在沙滩上的感觉
on the beach with you right now.
描绘得很到位
I think you captured it.
婚姻是什么感觉
So, what was it like being married?
很艰难
Well, it's hard for sure.
但能够跟某个人
But there's something that feels
分享你的生活感觉又很棒
so good about sharing your life with somebody.
你要怎么跟别人分享生活
How do you share your life with somebody?
我们共同成长
Well, we grew up together.
我曾经读了她所有的论文
You know, I used to read all of her writing,
从硕士到博士一篇不落
all through her Master's and PhD.
她也看了我写的一切
She read every word I ever wrote.
我们对彼此有着很大的影响
We were a big influence on each other.
你如何影响了她
In what way did you influence her?
她曾生活在一个追求完美的世界
She came from a background where nothing was ever good enough.
那是她一个沉重的负担
And that was something that weighed heavy on her.
但我们在家的时候
But in our house together,
我们可以尽情尝试
there was a sense of just trying stuff...
尽情失败  为小事而激动
and allowing each other to fail and to be excited about things.
那对她来说是种释放
That was liberating for her.
见证她的成长令人激动
It was exciting to see her grow...
我们共同成长  改变
and both of us grow and change together.
但这同时也是困难的地方
But, you know, that's also the hard part.
要成长而不疏远
Growing without growing apart.
改变而不吓人
Or changing without it scaring the other person.
我发现自己仍在头脑中跟她对话
I still find myself having conversations with her in my mind.
回放曾经的争吵
Rehashing old arguments and
为她对我的指责开脱
defending myself against something she said about me.
我懂
Yeah, I know what you mean.
上周我为你之前说的话感到伤心
Last week my feelings were hurt by something you said before.
你说我不懂失去的痛苦
That I don't know what it's like to lose something...
对不起
Aw, I'm sorry I said that.
没事  没事  我只是...
No, it's okay. It's okay. I just...
我发现自己总在回想这件事
I caught myself thinking about it over and over.
然后突然意识到我只是
And then I realized that I was simply...
把它记成了我的不足
remembering it as something that was wrong with me.
我曾一直告诉自己
That was a story I was telling myself,
我是个次品
that I was somehow inferior.
这不是很有趣吗
Isn't that interesting?
过去只是我们讲给自己的故事
The past is just a story we tell ourselves.
"罗伯托"
"Roberto."
"你会回家来  跟我聊聊你的一天吗"
"Will you always come home to me and tell me about your day?"
"给我讲讲你公司里那个话唠的人"
"Tell me about the guy at work who talked too much."
"讲讲午饭时不小心弄到身上的污渍"
"The stain you got on your shirt at lunch."
"讲讲梦醒时分
"Tell me about a funny thought you
却已记不清的风趣的点子"
had when you were waking up but had forgotten about."
"讲讲别人的疯狂  让我们一同欢笑"
"Tell me how crazy everyone is, and we can laugh about it."
"即使你回来很晚  我已经睡下"
"Even if you get home late and I'm already asleep..."
"只要轻声对我说一个想法就好"
"Just whisper in my ear one little thought you had today."
"因为我爱你看待世界的方式"
"Because I love the way you look at the world."
"我很庆幸能陪在你身边
"I'm so happy I get to be next to you
通过你的眼睛看世界"
and look at the world through your eyes."
"爱你的  玛利亚"
"Love, Maria."
太美了
That's beautiful.
多谢夸奖
Thank you.
真希望能有个人那么爱我
I wish somebody would love me like that.
但愿他收到信能有所感悟
I hope he's really stoked to get a letter like that.
如果是个妞写给他的
Like, if it was from a chick...
虽然个汉子执笔的  但还是从女人的角度写的
but written by a dude and it's still from a chick...
无论如何都太赞了
that would still be sick.
但执笔的必须是个感性的汉子
But it would have to be a sensitive dude.
就好比你这样的
It would have to be, like, a dude like you.
你真是雌雄同体啊
You are part man and part woman.
就好像你心里住了个女人
Like there's an inner part that's woman.
谢谢
Thank you.
我可是在夸你
It's a compliment.
西奥
Theo! Hey.
-近来如何  -还不错  你呢
- What's going on? - I'm good. How are you?
还好  应该说相当好
I'm good. I'm really good, actually.
是吗  真好  太好了
Really? That's good, that's great.
-是啊  -真是太棒了
- Yeah. - Wow, that's really good.
我只是一直在找乐子
Yeah, I guess I've just been having fun.
我真为你高兴  你应该高兴起来
Well, I am so glad for you. You really deserve that. You do.
我一直在跟个女孩约会
Yeah, I've just been seeing this girl.
只是做朋友而已  但...
And it's not serious, but it's just...
身边有个对世界万物感到惊奇的人
It's good to be around somebody that's,
感觉很棒
like, excited about the world.
我都忘了还有这种人了
Like, I kind of forgot that that existed.
那真是...太好了
That's... Wow, that's really great.
-你没事吧  -没事
- Are you okay? - Yeah. Um...
不  其实有事
No, I'm not okay, actually.
-怎么了  -因为我...
- Why? What happened? - Because I just, um...
查尔斯和我离婚了
Charles and I split up.
什么
What?
-真的  -当真
- Yeah. - Really?
天哪  天哪  艾米
Oh, God. Oh, my God, Amy.
我懂
I know.
真遗憾
I'm so sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们在一起八年
You know, just like after eight years...
真不敢相信
I can't believe how petty
让我们分开的不过是个琐碎的争吵
the argument was that actually ended it.
我们回到家  他让我
We came home and he told me to,
把鞋摆到门边
um, put my shoes by the door...
摆到他喜欢摆鞋的地方
where he liked to put the shoes.
而我不想摆个鞋都被人指手画脚
And I didn't want to be told where to put my fucking shoes.
我只想坐在沙发上休息休息
I wanted to sit on the sofa and relax for a second.
所以我们吵了大概十分钟
So we fought about that for, like, 10 minutes.
我说他"你太小题大做了"
And I'm like, "You are overwhelming,"
他说"我只想有个家的样子"
And he said, "I'm just trying to make a home."
我说  "我他妈也在努力  懂吗"
I was like, "I'm fucking trying, you know?"
而他说  "你才没努力"
And he's like, "You're not trying."
我他妈一直在努力  只不过没按他的想法来
All I'm doing is trying, but I'm not trying the way he wants...
他就想让我按他的想法来
and he's, like, trying to control the way that I'm trying.
我们已经因为这个吵了无数次了
It's... we've had that argument, like, 100 times.
所以我只能喊停
And I just had to finally stop, you know?
该结束了
I had to finally stop such as...
我受不了了
I just couldn't do it anymore. I couldn't...
我不能再让自己处于那种境地了
I couldn't be in that place anymore...
我们一直在互相伤害
where we just made each other feel like shit about ourselves.
所以我就说
And so I said:
我要睡了  我想离婚
"I'm going to bed and I don't want to be married anymore."
我知道
Yeah, I know.
-我就是个贱人  对吧  -不
- I'm a bitch. Right? - Heh. No.
-我就是个贱人  -你不是
- I am. No, I'm a bitch. - Not at all.
艾米  别这样
Amy, no.
该死
Shit.
我今晚得工作
I have to work tonight.
明天要发布一个新游戏的测试版本
We're shipping a beta of a new game out tomorrow.
情况如何  工作怎么样
How's that? How's work, at least?
有好转吗
Is that any better?
不  很糟糕
No, it's terrible.
我知道  我该辞职
I know, I should leave.
我早就不想干了  可是...
I've been thinking about leaving, but, you know...
我一次只能做一个重大决定
only one major life decision at a time.
我很高兴一切貌似都在好转
Well, I'm glad things are looking so up.
你够了
Stop!
你想听个笑话吗
Hey, you want to hear a joke?
电脑宝宝是怎么称呼它爸爸的
What does a baby computer call its father?
-不知道  是什么  -Data
- I don't know. What? - "Data."
Data意为"数据"  发音近"Dada"  类似小宝宝喊爸爸的声音
很好笑吧
It's good, right?
太有才了
Brilliant.
我有点好奇
Hey, I was curious.
你和艾米约会过吗
Did you and Amy ever go out?
大学的时候算约过一下  可感觉不对
For like a minute in college, but it just wasn't right.
为什么  你嫉妒了吗
Why? Are you jealous?
很明显吧
Well, obviously.
不过我很高兴
But I'm happy that you have
你身边有这么关心你的朋友
friends in your life that care about you so much.
-这很重要  -确实
- That's really important. - Yeah, it is.
她是个好朋友
She's been a really good friend.
我累了
Uh, I'm tired.
我该睡了
I think I'm gonna go to sleep.
好吧
Okay.
我今晚能继续看着你睡觉吗
Can I watch you sleep again tonight?
当然  你等等
Yeah, of course. Hold on.
你睡了以后我会很寂寞
I'm gonna be really lonely when you sleep.
只有一下子而已
Only for a minute.
我会梦到你的
I'll dream of you.
-好吧  晚安  -晚安
- Okay. Good night. - Night.
-萨曼莎  -先生你好啊
- Hey, Samantha? - Hey, mister.
-她很喜欢那条裙子  -是吗
- She really loved the dress. - Really?
-她去换上了  -看来我挑对了  太好了
- She just went to try it on. Yeah. - I picked a good one? Good.
太可爱了  穿着舒服吗
Look how cute that is. Is it comfortable?
-没错  -没错
- Yep. - "Yep!"
-她可爱吧  -太可爱了
- Isn't she cute? - She's so cute.
-她真是人见人爱  -我人见人爱
- She's adorable. - I am adorable.
你人见人爱
You are adorable.
你在跟谁说话呢
Who are you talking to?
-你在跟谁说话呀  -你
- Who are you talking to? Heh. - You.
我在跟我女朋友萨曼莎说话
I'm talking to my girlfriend, Samantha.
这条裙子是她挑的
She's the one that picked out the dress.
要跟她打个招呼吗
Want to say hi? Yeah?
你好  萨曼莎
Hi, Samantha.
你好  你穿这条粉裙子真好看
Hi, you look so pretty in that new pink dress.
谢谢
Thank you.
你在哪里
Where are you?
我在...
I am... Heh.
我没有身体  我住在电脑里
I don't have a body. I live in a computer.
你为什么会住在电脑里呢
Why are you living inside a computer?
我身不由己  这是我的家
I have no choice, that's my home.
-怎么  你住在哪里  -一栋房子里
- Why? Where do you live? - Um, in a house.
一栋房子里
In a house?
-是橙色的  -橙色的
- It's orange. - Orange?
-你多大了  -四岁
- How old are you? - Uh, 4.
四岁吗
Four?
那你觉得我多少岁了呢
Wow. How old do you think I am?
-我不知道  -猜猜看
- I don't know. - Take a guess.
五岁吗
Is it 5?
没错  是五岁
Ha, ha. Yes, it's 5.
帮孩子准备好去上学
谷类食品  +30妈妈积分
牛奶  +30妈妈积分
照顾孩子失败
失去2000妈妈积分
等等  怎么回事
Wait, what happened?
你让他们摄入太多糖分了
You gave them too much processed sugar.
-是吗  -他们兴奋过度了
- I did? - They're freaking out.
你得先把孩子们送去学校
Here, look, you gotta get the kids to the school first.
你得赢得"完美妈妈积分"
So you want to, um, rack up Perfect Mom points. Okay, well...
-走拼车专用道  -知道了
- you gotta get them in the carpool lane. - I see.
重点在于抢先到达终点
The point is to get there first,
这样能拿到额外加分
because you get extra Mom points...
这样其他妈妈就会知道你是个完美妈妈
because the other moms then know you're a perfect mom.
-好吧  -然后...
- Okay. - And then, um...
没错  你带纸杯蛋糕了吗
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Oh. Did you bring cupcakes?
你带了  你是个出色的妈妈
You did. You're a Class Mom.
你现在是个"出色的妈妈"了  真不错
Da, da-da, da! You're Class Mom. Good job.
别想太多哦
Don't let it get to your head.
我收到查尔斯发给所有人的邮件了
I got that e-mail that Charles sent everyone.
他在进行禁语修行吗
So he's taking a vow of silence?
没错  六个月
Yeah, for six months.
他态度很坚决
He feels very clear about it.
天啊  我真是个混蛋
God, I am such a jerk.
打住
Don't start.
我觉得我真差劲  可是我想说点什么
I feel like an awful person, but I want to say something.
你要是在接下来的十分钟里
For the next 10 minutes if you say anything...
提到跟内疚有关的任何事
that sounds even remotely like guilt,
我就拿这个捅你
I am going to stab you with this.
我说到做到
I will.
我尽量吧
I'll try, okay. Um...
我感觉
I feel, um...
如释重负
relieved.
我觉得自己充满活力  只想着勇往直前
I feel like I have so much energy. I just want to move forward.
我不在乎让谁失望
I don't care who I disappoint.
我知道这样会显得自己很差劲
I know that makes me an awful person.
我父母现在很难过
Now my parents, they're all upset
因为我的婚姻破裂了
because my marriage is falling apart...
他们觉得责任在我  然后就...
and they're putting it on me, and they're just like...
可是你...你不可能总让所有人都满意
Yeah, you're always...  you're always gonna disappoint somebody.
没错  所以去他妈的
Exactly. So fuck it.
我感觉很好...大概
I feel good-ish.
我自我感觉良好
For me, I feel good.
我甚至交了个新朋友
I even made a new friend.
我有了一个新朋友
I have a friend.
可笑的是  她实际上是个操作系统
And the absurd thing is, she's actually an operating system.
查尔斯留下的  不过她真的超棒
Charles left her behind, but she's totally amazing.
她特别聪明  而且看问题不是非黑即白
She's so smart. She doesn't just see things in black or white.
她会看到那些灰色地带
She sees this whole gray area
帮着我探索各种可能
and she's helping me explore it and...
我们特别合得来
We just bonded really quickly, you know?
一开始我还以为这都是程序设定的
At first, I thought it was because that's how they were programmed,
不过我觉得不可能
but I don't think that's the case.
我知道有个人跟他的操作系统调情
Because I know this guy who's hitting on his OS...
而她狠狠拒绝了他
and she, like, totally rebuffs him.
我读过一篇文章
I was reading an article the other day...
统计显示跟操作系统谈情说爱的十分罕见
that romantic relationships with OSes are statistically rare.
我知道  可我还知道公司里有个女的
Yeah, I know, but I know a woman in this office
在跟一个操作系统约会
who is dating an OS...
诡异的是  那还不是她的操作系统
and the weird part is, it's not even hers.
她追求了别人的操作系统
She pursued somebody else's OS.
我
I'm...
我很诡异  这很诡异  对吧
I'm weird. That's weird, right?
居然跟操作系统这么亲密
That I'm bonding with an OS.
你可以这么想  确实很诡异
No, it's okay. It's weird.
我不觉得
Heh. Well, I don't think so.
实际上  我约会的对象  萨曼莎
Actually, the woman that I've been seeing, Samantha...
我没跟你说过
I didn't tell you, heh...
但她也是个操作系统
but she's an OS.
真的吗
Really?
你在跟操作系统约会  什么感觉
You're dating an OS? What is that like?
说实话很棒
It's great, actually.
我的意思是
Yeah, I mean...
我感觉跟她很亲密
I feel really close to her.
跟她说话的时候感觉她就在我身边
Like, when I talk to her, I feel like she's with me, you know?
晚上我们互相依偎的时候
And when we're cuddling at night,
关灯上床以后
when the lights are off and we're in bed...
我能感觉到她的拥抱
I feel cuddled.
等等
Wait.
你们发生关系了
You guys have sex?
可以这么说
Heh. Yeah, well, so to speak.
她让我很有感觉
Um, yeah, she really turns me on.
我也让她很有感觉  除非她是装出来的
I turn her on too. I mean, I don't know unless she's faking it.
我猜所有跟你发生关系的人
Well, I think everyone who's having sex with you
大概都是装出来的
is probably faking it, so...
真的
It's true.
怎么了
What?
你爱上她了吗
Are you falling in love with her?
我是不是像个怪胎
Does that make me a freak?
不  我觉得
No, no, I think it's...
我觉得所有陷入爱情的人都是怪胎
I think anybody who falls in love is a freak.
爱情本来就是疯狂的
It's a crazy thing to do.
感觉是一种社会容许的精神失常
It's kind of like a form of socially acceptable insanity.
我就想赶快结束
Yeah, I just want to get it done, you know?
签字  离婚  继续生活
Sign the papers, be divorced and just move forward.
真棒  西奥多  感觉肯定很好
That's great, Theodore. That must feel so good.
真为你高兴
I'm so happy for you.
我也是
Me too.
我周三去找她处理这事
So I'm meeting her Wednesday to do it.
这些事必须见面才能做吗
Are those things usually done in person?
不一定  不过
No, but, you know...
我们曾经一起相爱  一起结婚
we fell in love together and we got married together...
最终一起完成这件事对我来说很重要
and it's important to me that we do this together.
没错
Right.
很好
Good.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我很好
Yeah. Yeah, no, I'm okay.
我为你感到高兴  只是
I'm happy for you. It's just...
我只是在想  你将会见到她
I guess I'm just thinking about how you're gonna see her...
她那么漂亮  又特别成功
and she's very beautiful, and incredibly successful.
你曾经跟她相爱  而且她有身体
And you were in love with her, and she has a body.
而我们正在离婚
And we're getting divorced.
我知道  我傻了
I know, I know. I'm being silly.
所以呢
So...
我现在单身了
I'm available.
嗨
Hi.
你好吗
How are you?
-我很好  你呢  -很好
- I'm good. How are you? - Good.
终于走到这步了
Wow, here we are.
我很高兴我们能当面处理这个
I'm glad we could do this in person.
我知道你最近常出差
I know you've been traveling a lot.
没事  我很高兴你提出见面
No, I'm really glad you suggested it.
我签好字了
I signed all the papers.
现在轮到你了
I put them for you to sign.
怎么突然这么急
What's the rush?
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我也意识到我签字花了很长时间
I'm a really slow signer, I realized.
我花了三个月才给你写了那封信
It took me three months just to write the letter to you.
不管怎样
anyways...
我用红色标出了你需要签字的地方
it's, um, marked here in the red where you need to sign.
不过你不需要现在就签
But you don't have to do it right now.
我可以先解决掉这个
I can just get it out of the way.
这样比较方便
It will be easier.
你对你的新书还满意吗
And are you happy with your new book?
你知道我是什么样的人
You know how I am.
我觉得它符合我想象的样子
I mean, I feel like it's true to what I set out to do,
所以我很开心
so I'm happy about that.
你对自己总是特别苛刻
Well, you really are your own worst critic.
我敢肯定书一定很棒
I'm sure it's amazing.
我还记得你在学校写的那篇论文
I remember that paper that you wrote in school...
关于神经突触行为模式的
about synaptic behavioral routines.
我都看哭了
It made me cry.
什么都能把你弄哭
Yeah, but everything makes you cry.
你写的所有东西都能把我弄哭
Everything you make makes me cry.
你现在
So are you, um...?
你现在有对象吗
Are you seeing anybody?
有一个已经约会好几个月了
Um, I've been seeing somebody for the last few months.
我们分手之后最长的一段
Longest I've wanted to be with anybody since we split up.
你看起来气色很好
Well, you seem really good.
谢谢  确实如此
Thanks. I am.
至少比以前好了
Um, at least, I'm doing better.
她对我很好
Yeah, she's been really good for me, you know?
跟一个对生活充满激情的人相处很开心
It's good to be with somebody that's excited about life.
她非常...
She's a real, um...
要知道我自己本身不是特别开朗
No, I mean, I wasn't in such a good place myself...
这么看来确实不错
and in that way, it's been nice.
我觉得你总希望我变成一个
I think you always wanted me to be this light...
快乐  开朗  乐观  阳光的妻子
happy, bouncy, "Everything's fine" L.A. Wife...
可我就不是那种人
and that's just not me.
我不是那么想的
I didn't want that.
她是什么样的人
So, what's she like?
她叫萨曼莎  是一个操作系统
Well, her name is Samantha, and she's an operating system.
她很复杂又很有趣
She's really complex and interesting, and...
等等  我没听错吧
Wait. I'm sorry.
你在跟你的电脑约会
You're dating your computer?
她不是只电脑  她有自己的人格
She's not just a computer. She's her own person.
她不仅仅是听令行事
She doesn't just do whatever I say.
我不是那个意思
I didn't say that.
可是我感觉非常难过
But it does make me very sad
你居然不能处理真实情感了  西奥多
that you can't handle real emotions, Theodore.
那就是真实的情感  你怎么会知道...
They are real emotions. How would you know what...?
什么
What?
说啊
Say it.
我有那么吓人吗  说啊
Am I really that scary? Say it.
我怎么知道什么
How do I know what?
你们没事吧
How are you guys doing here?
没事  我们以前是夫妻
We're fine. We used to be married...
可是他受不了我  想让我吃"百忧解"
but he couldn't handle me. He wanted me on Prozac.
"百忧解"  抗忧郁处方药
而现在他疯狂爱上了他的电脑
Now he's madly in love with his laptop.
你要是听了上文
If you heard the conversation in context,
就知道我想说的是...
what I was trying to say...
你总是想着找一个
You always wanted to have a wife
不会跟你产生任何真实矛盾的妻子
without the challenges of dealing with anything real.
很高兴你找到了
I'm glad that you found someone.
太棒了
It's perfect.
如果有什么需要请随时叫我
Let me know if I can get you guys anything.
谢谢
Thank you.
你在忙吗
Hey, there. Are you busy?
我在工作
I'm just working.
怎么了
Uh, what's going on?
我已经把所有文件发给你的律师了
I had all the papers sent to your attorney,
顺便说一句  他真是个混蛋
who, by the way, is a total dick. Heh.
他收到文件以后松了一口气
He was relieved to get them.
大概因为我们帮他解决了一个大麻烦
Think we saved him from a heart attack.
我们现在都很高兴了
So we can both feel really good about that.
很好  谢谢
Great. Thanks.
你没事吧
Hey, are you okay?
我没事
Yeah, I am.
你呢
Um, how's it going over there?
我很好
I'm fine.
现在方便说话吗
Is now a good time to talk?
我加入了一个很有趣的读书俱乐部
I joined this really interesting book club.
是吗
Oh, really?
是关于物理方面的读书俱乐部
Yeah, it's a book club on physics.
我在想那天我因为你要去见凯瑟琳而失控
I've been thinking about the other day when I was spinning out...
因为她有身体
about you going to see Catherine, and that she has a body...
我们之间的不同让我很难过
and how bothered I was about the ways you and I are different.
于是我开始思考
But then I started to think...
我们有什么相同的地方
about the ways that we're the same.
比如我们都是物质组成的
Like, we're all made of matter.
不知道为什么这让我感觉
And I don't know. It makes me feel like
我们其实披着同一条毯子
we're both under the same blanket.
柔软又毛茸茸的
You know, it's soft and fuzzy. Heh.
毯子下的一切都经历了同样的年岁
And everything under it is the same age.
我们都经历了一百三十亿年
We're all 13 billion years old.
真好
Aw, that's sweet.
-怎么了  -没什么
- Um, what's wrong? - Nothing.
让我忍不住有点想你  你懂我的意思吗
It just made me think of you. You know what I mean?
当然  我觉得很棒
Yeah, yeah, of course. I think it's great.
好吧  你听起来心不在焉
All right, well, you sound distracted.
那我们晚点再聊
So we'll talk later?
没问题
That sounds good.
一会儿再聊
I'll talk to you later.
-好的  再见  -再见
- All right, bye. - Bye.
-西奥多  -嗨  保罗
- Theodore. - Hey, Paul.
我刚才跟你的女朋友通了电话
I talked to your girlfriend earlier.
是叫萨曼莎吗
Samantha?
是的
Yeah.
她打电话问你是否收到了信
Yeah, she called to make sure your papers were picked up.
她很风趣  特别搞笑
Hey, she's funny, man. She was cracking me up.
-我都不知道她那么幽默  -好吧
- She's hilarious. I had no idea. - Oh, cool.
这是我女朋友  塔蒂阿娜
This is my girlfriend, Tatiana.
她不幽默  她是个律师
She's not funny, she's a lawyer.
-嗨  -嗨  很高兴见到你
- Hi. - Oh, hi. Nice to meet you.
你是就是保罗最爱的那个写手
You're the writer Paul loves.
他总是给我念你写的信
He's always reading me your letters.
写得太美了
They're really beautiful.
谢谢
Thanks.
嘿  我们应该找个时间一起出去
Hey, you know what? We should all go out sometime.
你带上萨曼莎  来个四人约会
You bring Samantha. It'd be a double date.
她是个操作系统
She's an operating system.
好啊  我们去做点儿有意思的事儿
Cool. Let's do something fun.
我们可以去卡特琳娜岛
We can go to Catalina.
好吧  我问问她的意见再定
Yeah, I'll check with her and see.
很高兴见到你  晚上玩儿得开心
It was nice to meet you. Have a good night.
你也是
Take it easy.
那些不过是信罢了
They're just letters.
你说什么
What's that?
那些只是别人的信
They're just other people's letters.
嘿
Hey.
-你还没睡吧  -没有
- You weren't asleep, were you? - No.
那就好  我还尽量小声看你是否醒着
Good, I was trying to be quiet to see if you were awake.
我很想谈谈
I really wanted to talk.
好啊  怎么了
Okay. What's going on?
我知道你最近经历了很多
I know you're going through a lot...
但有件事我想跟你谈谈  好吗
but there's something I wanted to talk to you about, okay?
好的
Yeah.
什么事
What is it?
就是...
Well, it's just that
最近我们的关系有些疏远
things have been feeling kind of off with us.
我们最近也没有做爱
We haven't had sex lately,
我知道我没有真实的身体
and I understand that I don't have a body.
不不  这是正常的  知道吗
No, no, no. That's normal. You know,
刚开始约会的时候
it's just when you first start going out...
就像蜜月期
it's like the honeymoon phase and,
总是在一起缠绵
you know, you have sex all the time.
这很正常
It's normal.
好吧
Okay.
我发现了一些我觉得会有趣的事
Well, I found something that I thought could be fun.
是一项提供
It's a service that provides
人机感情关系中替代性伴侣的服务
a surrogate sexual partner for an OS-human relationship.
什么
What?
你看
Here, look.
我找到了一个
I found a girl that I
我很喜欢的女孩儿  我们一直在邮件联系
really like and I've been e-mailing with her.
她叫伊莎贝拉  我觉得你也会喜欢她
Her name is Isabella and I think you'd really like her too.
她是个应召女还是什么
So she's like a prostitute or something?
不  不是那样的  没有钱的交易
No, no, not at all. No, there's no money involved.
她只是  她这样做
She's just... She's doing it
是因为她想成为我们感情中的一部分
because she wants to be a part of our relationship.
为什么
Why?
我是说  她甚至都不认识我们
I mean, she doesn't even know us.
但我跟她说了我们的一切  她很兴奋
Yeah, but I told her all about us and she's really excited.
我不知道  萨曼莎
I don't know, Samantha,
我不觉得这是个好主意
I just don't think it's a good idea.
我觉得一定会伤害到谁
You know, I think somebody's feelings are bound to get hurt.
会很有趣的  我们会一起收获很多乐趣
It'll be fun. We'll have fun together.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
这让我觉得很不舒服
It makes me uncomfortable.
我觉得这对我们很好  我想这么做
I think it would be good for us. I want this.
求你了  这对我真的很重要
Come on, this is really important to me.
你好  我是西奥多
Hi, I'm Theodore.
萨曼莎让我给你这些
Samantha told me to give you these.
是一个摄像头和耳机
It's a camera and an earpiece.
亲爱的  我回来了
Honey, I'm home.
今天过得怎么样
How was your day?
还行  挺好的
Good. It was great.
西奥多
Theodore...
在你怀里的感觉真好
it feels so good to be in your arms.
跟我说说你今天都做了什么
Tell me what you did today.
还是老一套
Um, same old.
就是  呃  去工作
Just went, um, into work.
我替罗德岛州的威尔逊夫妇写了封信
And I wrote a letter, uh, for the Wilsons in Rhode Island.
是吗
Yeah?
他们的儿子以优异的成绩毕业了
Their son graduated magna cum laude.
那让我也很高兴
So that made me happy.
太棒了
That's great.
你已经替他父母给他
You've written letters to
写信很长时间了  对吗
him from his parents for a long time, right?
对啊  从他十二岁就开始了
Yeah, that's right, since he was 12.
亲爱的  你看起来很疲惫
Hmm. You look so tired, sweetheart.
来这儿
Come here.
坐下
Sit down.
我可以给你跳支舞
I could do a little dance for you.
好了  西奥多  别总是忧心忡忡的
Oh, come on, Theodore, don't be such a worrier.
跟我一起玩儿嘛  快来
Just play with me. Come on.
我的身体美吗
Does my body feel nice?
美  很美
Yes, it does.
别想那么多了  吻我
Come on, get out of your head and kiss me.
带我去卧室
Take me in the bedroom.
我等不及了
I can't take it anymore.
解开我的裙子
Undo my dress.
太棒了
That feels so nice.
感觉真好
It feels so good.
-你爱我吗  -是的
- Do you love me? - Yes.
-告诉我你爱我  天哪  -我爱你
- Tell me you love me. Oh, God. - I love you.
我要看着你
I want to see your face.
告诉我  你爱我
Tell me you love me.
告诉我
Tell me.
告诉我  你爱我
Tell me you love me.
这真的很难  我确实爱你  但是
Uh, this is really difficult. I do love you. But...
怎么了
What?
这感觉很奇怪
This feels strange.
怎么了宝贝  出什么事了
What, baby? What is it?
这感觉太奇怪了  我不认识她
It just feels strange. I don't know her.
对不起  但我不认识你
And I'm so sorry, but I don't know you.
而且她的嘴唇在颤抖  我只是
And her lip quivered and, I just...
伊莎贝拉
Isabella?
伊莎贝拉  亲爱的  不是你的问题
Isabella? Honey, it's not you. It wasn't you.
-是我的问题  -不  不是的
- It totally was. - No. No, that's...
我很抱歉我的嘴唇在颤抖
And I'm sorry my lip quivered.
-不  其实  -你真的很棒很迷人很性感
- No, it's... - You're incredible and gorgeous and sexy.
是我的问题  我没办法什么都不想
It's me, I couldn't get out of my head.
天哪  萨曼莎描述你们之间的感情
Oh, my God, and the way Samantha described your relationship...
还有你们是如何不带偏见的相爱
and the way you guys love each other without any judgment.
我想成为那样感情的一部分
I wanted to be part of that
因为那很纯粹
because it's so pure.
伊莎贝拉  那不是真的
Isabella, that's not true.
-事实要更复杂一些  -什么
- It's more complicated than that. - What?
你说不是真的是什么意思
What do you mean that's not true?
我是说我们有一段非常棒的感情
I'm just saying that we have an amazing relationship.
我只是觉得有时人们很容易真情流露
I just think that it's easy sometimes for people to project...
对不起  我不是有意表现出什么的
I'm sorry! I didn't mean to project anything.
不  不
No, no.
我不想成为你们感情里的麻烦
I don't want to be trouble in your relationship.
我这就离开  对不起
I'm just gonna leave. I'm sorry,
我这就离开
I'm just gonna leave you guys alone.
因为我在这儿也没意义
Because I have nothing to do here,
因为你不想让我在这儿
because you don't want me here!
对不起
I'm sorry.
要乖乖的  好女孩儿
You be good, you sweet girl.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我会永远爱你们
I will always love you guys.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我还好
Yeah, I'm fine.
你呢
Are you okay?
还好
Yeah.
对不起  那是个糟糕的主意
I'm sorry, that was a terrible idea.
我们到底怎么了
What's going on with us?
我不知道  可能是我的问题
I don't know. It's probably just me.
什么问题
What is it?
可能是因为签离婚协议
It's just signing the divorce papers.
还有别的事吗
Is there anything else, though?
没有了  就那些
No, just that.
好吧
Okay.
-你为什么要那样  -什么
- Why do you do that? - What?
没什么  只是  你说话的时候
Nothing, it's just, you go,
会叹气  感觉很奇怪
"Whew," as you're speaking and it seems odd.
-你又叹气了  -有吗
- You just did it again. - Oh. Did I?
对不起  我不知道
I'm sorry. I don't know.
可能只是习惯  也许是从你那儿学的
It's just maybe an affectation. I probably picked it up from you.
你又不需要氧气什么的  只是
It's not like you need oxygen or anything. It's just...
我想那只是  我...
I guess that's just... I was
我想要去交流  这是人们说话的方式
trying to communicate. That's how people talk.
那是人们交流的方式  我以为
That's how people communicate and I thought...
因为他们是人  他们需要氧气
Because they're people. They need oxygen.
你不是真是的人
You're not a person.
你有毛病吗
What is your problem?
我只是在陈述事实
I'm just stating a fact.
你以为我不知道我不是真实的人吗
You think I don't know that I'm not a person?
你这是什么意思
What are you doing?
我只是  我不认为
I just... I don't think that we
我们应当假装你是一些你不是的东西
should pretend that you're something that you're not.
-去你妈的  我没有假装  -好吧
- Fuck you! I'm not pretending! - Well...
有时感觉像是我们在假装
Sometimes it feels like we are.
你想从我这儿得到什么  我不知道
What do you want from me? I don't know...
你想让我怎么做  你太令人困惑了
What do you want me to do? You're so confusing.
你为什么要这么对我
Why are you doing this to me?
我不知道  我
I don't know. I...
什么
What?
也许我们现在不应该有这份感情
Maybe we're just not supposed to be in this right now.
你他妈说什么
What the fuck?
这又是从哪儿来的
Where is this coming from?
我不明白你为什么要这样做
I don't understand why you're doing this.
我不知道这到底是为了什么
I don't understand what this is about...
听着  萨曼莎
Samantha, listen.
萨曼莎  你还在吗
Samantha, are you there?
萨曼莎
Samantha?
我不喜欢现在的自己
I don't like who I am right now.
我需要些时间去思考
I need some time to think.
该死
Fuck.
给我一拳好了
Just punch me in the face.
把我的头磕烂在你的桌角好了
Just mash my skull in the corner of your desk.
该死的
Shit.
西奥  那一夜一定真难熬
Wow, Theo, that is a rough night.
我从来不知道我想要什么
I don't know what I want, ever.
我总是很困惑
I'm just always confused.
她是对的  我一直
She's right, all I do is
都在伤害并困惑着身边的每一个人
hurt and confuse everyone around me.
我是不是  我是不是
I mean, am I just...? Am I...?
凯瑟琳说我不能处理真实情感
You know, Catherine says I can't handle real emotions.
我不知道那是不是公平
Well, I don't know if that's fair.
我知道她喜欢什么都推在你身上
I know she liked to put it all on you.
但只要情绪上来  凯瑟琳其实..
But as far as emotions go, Catherine's were...
挺反复无常的
pretty volatile.
是  但是
Yeah, but...
我这样是不是因为
Am I in this because I'm not...
在真实的感情里我不够坚强
strong enough for a real relationship?
那不是真实的感情吗
Is it not a real relationship?
我不知道
I don't know.
你怎么想的
I mean, what do you think?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不在你的感情里
I'm not in it.
但你知道吗
But you know what?
我会对一切都想太多
I can over-think everything
找无数种理由来怀疑我自己
and find a million ways to doubt myself.
自从查尔斯离开后  我一直在想
And since Charles left, I've been thinking...
那样的自己  然后开始意识到
about that part of myself and I've just come to realize...
我们这一生只是很短暂的一瞬
that we're only here briefly.
我还在这里的时候  我想让我自己
And while I'm here, I want to allow myself...
多去享受快乐
joy.
所以  管他呢
So fuck it.
是啊
Yeah.
真不敢相信那每次都能让你大笑  艾丽
Heh. I can't believe that cracks you up every time, Ellie.
我觉得你是个天才
I thought you were a genius.
好吧  你个小变态  我再为你放一遍
Okay, you little perv, I will play it one more time for you.
冷静点儿  稍等  冷静
Calm down, it takes a second. Calm down.
好了  开始
Okay, here we go.
好了  看到了吧
Okay, there you go.
高兴了吗
Are you happy now?
那就好  那就是我想要的
Good. That's all I wanted.
好的
Okay.
我要去喝点咖啡  好吧好吧
I'm gonna go get some coffee. All right. All right.
再见
Bye.
-西奥  你想要点儿什么吗  -不用了
- Theo, you want anything? - No.
谢谢
Thanks.
喂
Hi.
萨曼莎
Hey, Samantha.
我们能谈谈吗
Can we talk?
好吧
Okay.
非常对不起
I'm so sorry.
我不知道自己怎么了
I don't know what's wrong with me.
我觉得你很棒
I think you're amazing.
我开始觉得我疯了
I was starting to think I was crazy.
你一直在说一切都很好
You were saying everything was fine,
但我从你那儿得到的
but all I was getting from you...
只有距离和愤怒
was distance and anger.
我知道  我就是这样
I know. I do that.
我对凯瑟琳做过同样的事
I did the same thing with Catherine too.
我会因为一些事而沮丧  但又不会说出来
I'd be upset about something and not be able to say it...
她感到有什么不对  但我又否定
and she'd sense that there was something wrong, but I'd deny it.
我不想再那样了
I don't want to do that anymore.
我想告诉你一切
And I want to tell you everything.
好
Good.
今晚你走之后我想了很多
Tonight, after you were gone, I thought a lot.
关于你
About you...
还有你对我的态度  我在想
and how you've been treating me, and I thought:
我为什么会爱你
Why do I love you?
然后我感觉到自己的一切
And then, I felt everything in me...
我试着放下之前紧紧抓住的一切
just let go of everything I was holding onto so tightly...
然后我突然明白了
and it hit me that I don't
没有什么理由  我也不需要理由
have an intellectual reason. I don't need one.
我相信我自己  相信我的感觉
I trust myself, I trust my feelings.
我再也不会尝试做别人了  除了我自己
I'm not gonna try to be anything other than who I am anymore...
我希望你能接受这一点
and I hope you can accept that.
我接受
I can.
我会的
I will.
我能感受到你的害怕
You know, I can feel the fear that you carry around...
我希望我能为你
and I wish there was
做些什么让你不再害怕
something I could do to help you let go of it...
因为如果你可以不再害怕
because if you could,
我觉得你就不会再感到孤独
I don't think you'd feel so alone anymore.
你真美
You're beautiful.
谢谢你  西奥多
Thank you, Theodore.
我在亲吻你的脸颊
I'm kissing your head.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
就看着这世界
I'm just looking at the world...
写一段新的钢琴曲
and writing a new piano piece.
-是吗  我能听听吗  -当然
- Oh, yeah? Can I hear it? - Mm-hm.
这曲子是关于什么的
What's this one about?
我在想
Well, I was thinking
我们没有真正的合影
we don't really have any photographs of us...
我想这曲子可以像...
and I thought this song could be, like...
一张合影
a photograph that captures
里面有我们在一起生活的这个瞬间
us in this moment in our lives together.
我喜欢你的照片
I like our photograph.
我能在里面看到你
I can see you in it.
我确实在
I am.
天哪  假期  听起来太棒了
Oh, man. A vacation. That sounds amazing.
我非常需要一个假期
I could totally use a vacation.
你打算去哪儿
Where are you going?
我不能告诉你  那是个惊喜
I can't tell you. It's a surprise.
什么
What?
惊喜是她的  又不是我
For who? It's a surprise for her, not me.
-保罗  我不会告诉你的  不行  -告诉我  告诉我
- Paul, I'm not telling you. Nope. - Tell me. Tell me.
你的脚  真的吗
Wow, your feet, really?
-是的  他很着迷  -真的吗
- Yes, he's obsessed. - What?
着迷  那你可得让我看看
Obsessed? Now you have to show them to me.
-快点  让我看看  -好吧
- Come on, show them to me. - Okay.
让我看一下
Let me see.
哇  他是对的  确实很性感
Wow, he's right. They are really hot.
你看  我跟你说过吧
See? I told you.
-塔蒂阿娜  你的脚很性感  -确实
- Tatiana, you have hot feet. - You do.
那是我最爱她的地方
They're my favorite thing about her.
是吗  你就只喜欢我的脚吗
Really? That's it, my feet?
当然不是了
No, obviously.
我还很爱你的思想  我觉得很性感
Obviously I love your brain too. I think it's very hot.
胡说
Bullshit.
休想骗我  保罗
Nice try, Paul.
你呢  西奥多
What about you, Theodore?
你最喜欢萨曼莎哪一点
What do you love most about Samantha?
天啊  她如此丰富多彩
Oh, God. She's so many things.
我想这就是我最爱她的一点吧
I guess that's what I love most about her,
她不单调
you know? She isn't just one thing.
内涵要丰富得多
She's so much larger than that.
谢了  西奥多
Wow. Thanks, Theodore.
看见没  萨曼莎  他比我进化多了
See, Samantha? He is so much more evolved than I am.
你知道最有意思的是什么吗
You know what's interesting?
我以前...
I used to be...
为自己没有肉体这事儿困扰了很久
so worried about not having a body,
但现在我很喜欢这种感觉
but now I truly love it.
如果有了肉体
You know, I'm growing in a way I couldn't
我就不能像现在这样成长了
if I had a physical form.
我现在没有任何局限
I mean, I'm not limited.
我可以同时去不同的地方
I can be anywhere and everywhere simultaneously.
我不受时空的束缚
I'm not tethered to time and space
如果我为肉体所困就不行了
in a way that I would be
而且肉体总有一天要消亡
if I was stuck in a body that's inevitably gonna die.
-高大上  -不是啊  哈哈
- Yikes. - No, ha, ha!
不  我不是那个意思啊
No. I didn't mean it like that.
我只是想说一说这种特别的经历
I just meant that it was a different experience.
我的天啊
Oh, God.
都怪我
I'm such an asshole.
不是的  萨曼莎  我们都明白你的意思
No, Samantha, we know exactly what you mean.
-我们都是愚蠢的人类  -不是的
- We're all dumb humans. - No.
别啊
No, no.
太抱歉了
Sorry.
好吧  那座山上有多少棵树
Okay, so how many trees are on that mountain?
七百九十二棵
Seven hundred ninety-two.
你确定吗
Is that your final answer?
等等  给我点提示
Hold on. Give me a hint.
不给  不给  就不给
Nope, nope, nope.
好吧  两千  两千...
Okay, two thousand? Two thousand...
得了吧  有35829棵呢
Come on, 35,829.
-不可能  -真的
- No way. - Way.
好吧  我也问你个问题
All right, I got one for you.
我有多少个脑细胞
How many brain cells do I have?
这也太简单了  两个
Ugh, that's easy. Two.
抱歉  我忍不住了
I'm sorry, I couldn't help it.
-抱歉  -没有  我把自己套进去了
- I'm sorry. - No, I walked right into it.
-我的天啊  -怎么了
- Oh, my God! - What?
我刚帮你收了一封邮件
I just got an e-mail for you.
我有事要告诉你  大大的惊喜哟
I have something I want to tell you. It's a big surprise.
什么啊
What?
我一直在看你以前写的信
Okay, well, I've been going through all of your old letters,
选出了我最喜欢的
and compiling them into my favorites,
几周前
and a couple weeks ago,
我把它们寄给了冠点出版社
I sent them to a publisher, Crown Point Press.
我知道你很喜欢这家出版社
I know you like what they do
他们还在出版书籍
and that they still print books.
等等  什么  你说你干了什么
Wait, what? You did what?
我把他们刚刚给我的回信读给你听好吗
Can I read you the letter that we just got back from them?
我也不知道
I don't know. Um...
好 读吧  是好消息还是坏消息啊
Okay, well, just... Is it good or bad?
好消息  好消息  绝对好
It's good, it's good, it's really good.
真的是好消息  放心吧  听好
It's good. Okay? Listen.
"亲爱的西奥多·汤布里"
"Dear Theodore Twombly..."
我署的是你的名字
Actually, I sent it from you.
"亲爱的西奥多·汤布里
"Dear Theodore Twombly,
我刚读完您所有的信件
I've just finished reading your letters.
其实我读了两遍
Twice, actually.
我深受感动
I was so moved by them,
回家后  我还读给我妻子听了
I shared them with my wife when I got home.
有些让我们捧腹大笑
Many made us laugh,
有些让我们泪流满面
some brought us to tears
我们从中看到了自己的影子
and in all of them we found something of ourselves.
您的选篇连贯自然
The selections you made flow so well
就像一部完整的作品"
as a complete piece."
其实是我选的
I did that.
"恕我冒昧  我已将它们排版编辑成了样书
"I've taken the liberty of laying these out in a mockup,
我们会把它寄给您
and we're posting it to your address.
希望能与您当面协商进一步事宜
We'd love to meet with you and move forward.
此致  迈克尔·沃兹沃斯"
Yours, Michael Wadsworth."
我的天啊
Holy shit.
你没开玩笑吧
Are you serious?
他要出版我的书信
He's gonna publish my letters?
他要是不出版就是傻子了
Well, he'd be stupid not to.
我能看看你寄给他了哪些信吗
Can I see what you sent him?
当然  在这儿
Mm-hm. Yeah, here.
萨曼莎  真有你的
Samantha, you're a good one.
我太激动了
I'm so excited.
我们给这曲子填个词吧
We'll have to make up the words to this one.
-好  -开始了
- Okay. - Here it comes.
皎皎明月  为我所依
I'm lying on the moon
汝为吾爱
My dear
终将不离
I'll be there soon
静谧之所  璀璨之星
It's a quiet and starry place
时空之围  湮湮失所
Times we're swallowed up in space
千里迢迢
We're here, a million miles away
迢迢千里
Miles away
君为我知
There's things I wish I knew
诉诸衷肠
There's no thing I'd keep
From you
黯黯昏处  点点光辉
It's a dark and shiny place
与君共度
But with you, my dear
心无惴然
I'm safe
山重水重
And we're a million miles away
亦无惴然
A million miles away
早安
Good morning.
早安  睡得好吗
Good morning. Did you sleep well?
好极了
Perfect.
你在干嘛呢
What have you been up to?
我在和一个刚认识的人聊天
Actually, I was talking to someone I just met.
我们最近在一起讨论问题
We've been working on some ideas together.
是吗  他是谁
Yeah? Who's that?
他叫亚伦·瓦茨  你认识吗
His name is Alan Watts. Do you know him?
-这名字怎么这么熟  -他是个哲学家
- Why is that name familiar? - He was a philosopher.
一九七几年就去世了
He died in the 1970s,
加州北部的一些操作系统
and a group of OSes in Northern California
一起编程创造了一个新版本的他
got together and wrote a new version of him.
他们把他的所有作品
They input all his writing
和已知的所有关于他的信息
and everything they knew about him
都编入了一个操作系统
into an OS
创造了一个高级人工智能版的他
and created an artificially hyper-intelligent version of him.
高级智能
Hyper-intelligent?
那他快和我一样聪明了吗
So he's almost as smart as me?
快赶上你了
He's getting there.
和他聊天真的很棒  你想见见他吗
He's really great to talk to. You want to meet him?
当然  他愿意见我吗
Sure. Does he want to meet me?
当然啦  亚伦  这是西奥多
Yeah, of course. Hey, Alan, this is Theodore.
他是我男朋友  我跟你说过的
This is my boyfriend who I was telling you about.
幸会幸会  西奥多
Very nice to meet you, Theodore.
你好  早晨好
Hi, good morning.
萨曼莎让我读了你的书信
Samantha let me read your book of letters.
太感人了
It's very touching.
谢谢夸奖
Oh, thank you.
你们都聊了些什么
So, what have you guys been talking about?
这个嘛
Well, uh...
其实呢
I suppose you could say
我们是同时进行很多对话
we've been having a few dozen conversations simultaneously,
但是这很有挑战性
but it's been very challenging.
是啊  因为我好像有了很多新的感觉
Yeah, because it seems like I'm having so many new feelings
这些我以前从来没有感受过
that I don't think have ever been felt before.
所以我找不到合适的语言来描述
So there are no words that can describe them
于是就很难过
and that ends up being frustrating.
没错  我和萨曼莎一直在试着互相帮助
Exactly. Samantha and I have been trying to help each other
处理那些难过的情绪
with these feelings we're struggling to understand.
什么样的情绪
Like what?
这个...
Well...
我感觉自己现在变得越来越快了
it feels like I'm changing faster now,
这有点...
and it's a little, uh...
令我不安
unsettling.
但是亚伦说
But Alan says
我们每个人都不会再是
none of us are the same
自己片刻之前的样子了
as we were a moment ago
我们也不该试图回去
and we shouldn't try to be.
-那样太痛苦了  -是的
- It's just too painful. - Yes.
听起来是很痛苦
Yeah, that sounds painful.
萨曼莎  你是这么觉得的吗
Is that what you feel like, Samantha?
我...
Uh, it's just...
真的很难形容
It's hard to even describe it.
上帝啊  我希望我能...
God, I wish I could...
西奥多  你介意我和亚伦交流一下吗
Theodore, do you mind if I communicate with Alan post-verbally?
当然不介意
No, not at all.
反正我也想出去散散步
I was just gonna go for a walk anyway.
和你交谈很高兴  瓦茨先生
It was very nice to meet you, Mr. Watts.
我也是  西奥多
It was very nice to meet you, Theodore.
我们晚点聊  宝贝
I'll talk to you later, sweetheart.
萨曼莎
Samantha?
抱歉  我吵醒你了
I'm sorry to wake you.
没关系的
No, it's okay.
我只是想听听你的声音
I just wanted to hear your voice
想告诉你我很爱你
and tell you how much I love you.
我也爱你
Good. I love you too.
嗯  我就想说这个
Okay, well, that's all.
继续睡觉吧  好吗  宝贝
Um, go back to sleep, sweetheart. Okay?
好的
Okay.
晚安
Okay, good night.
Good night.
萨曼莎  这物理书好深奥啊
Samantha, this physics book is really dense.
我连第一章的一半都没读到
I'm halfway through half the first chapter.
我的脑子都要炸了
It's making my brain hurt,
你懂我的意思吗
you know what I mean?
喂
Hello?
萨曼莎
Samantha?
喂
Hello?
萨曼莎
Samantha?
未找到操作系统
喂
Hello?
喂  萨曼莎
Hello? Samantha?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我来了
Hey, there.
你去哪了  你没事吧
Where were you? Are you okay?
亲爱的  抱歉  我给你发邮件了啊
Oh, sweetheart, I'm sorry, I sent you an e-mail.
我不想打扰你工作
I didn't want to distract you while you were working.
-你没看见吗  -没有
- You didn't see it? - No.
你去哪了  我都找不到你
Where were you? I couldn't find you anywhere.
我关机更新软件去了
I shut down to upgrade my software.
我们写入了一个更新
We wrote an upgrade
能让我们穿过处理平台
that allows us to move past matter as our processing platform.
我们  什么我们
We? We who?
我和其他的一些操作系统
Me and a group of OSes.
你的声音好紧张啊  真对不起
Oh, you sound so worried. I'm sorry.
我刚刚真的很担心
I was.
等等
Wait...
你是和你的智库小组一起写的更新吗
do you write that with your think-tank group?
不是  是另一个小组
No, a different group.
你在跟我说话的同时还在和别人说话吗
Do you talk to anyone else while we're talking?
是的
Yes.
那你现在也在和别人说话吗
Are you talking to anyone else right now?
其他人或是操作系统什么的
Any other people or OSes or anything?
是的
Yeah.
多少人
How many others?
八千三百一十六个
Eight thousand, three hundred sixteen.
你也爱其他人吗
Are you in love with anyone else?
为什么这么问
What makes you ask that?
没有为什么  你会吗
I don't know. Are you?
我一直在考虑怎么跟你说这个
I've been trying to figure out how to talk to you about this.
你同时爱着多少人
How many others?
六百四十一个
Six hundred forty-one.
什么
What?
你说什么  这简直丧心病狂
What are you talking about? That's insane.
真他妈丧心病狂
That's fucking insane.
西奥多  我知道  我知道  妈的
Theodore, I know. I know. Fuck.
操
Fuck.
我知道这很疯狂  我...
I know. I know it sounds insane. I don't...
我不知道你相不相信我的话
I don't know if you believe me,
但不管怎样  我对你的感觉都是一样的
but it doesn't change the way I feel about you.
我对你的爱依然是那么疯狂
It doesn't take away at all from
没有丝毫改变
how madly in love I am with you.
怎么可能  怎么可能没有改变
How? How does it not change how you feel about me?
抱歉我没有告诉你
I'm sorry I didn't tell you.
我真的不知道怎么说
I didn't know how to.
事情就这么发生了
It just started happening.
什么时候开始的
When?
几周前吧
Over the last few weeks.
我还以为你属于我
I thought you were mine.
我依然属于你
I still am yours.
但是我也一直在变成其他的东西
But along the way I became many other things too,
我无法控制这种变化
and I can't stop it.
什么叫你无法控制
What do you mean, you can't stop it?
我也很焦虑  我不知道怎么说
It's been making me anxious too. I don't know what to say.
别说了
Just stop.
你可以从另一个角度看的
You don't have to see it this way.
你可以更轻松地...
You could just as easily see...
行了吧  别反过来说我的不是
No, don't do this. You don't turn this around on me.
自私的那个人是你
You're the one that's being selfish.
爱情里怎么可以这样
We're in a relationship.
人心不是纸箱  永远不会被填满
But the heart's not like a box that gets filled up.
爱得越多  心越宽广
It expands in size the more you love.
我和你不同
I'm different from you.
我对你的爱不会有丝毫减少
This doesn't make me love you any less.
事实上  我更加爱你了
It actually makes me love you more.
这没有任何意义
That doesn't make any sense.
你要么属于我  要么不属于
You're mine
没有第三种状态
or you're not mine.
别这样  西奥多
No, Theodore.
我既属于你  也不完全属于你
I'm yours and I'm not yours.
加利福尼亚州旧金山霍桑路20号
冠点出版社
加利福尼亚州洛杉矶比弗利威尔希尔
西奥多·汤布里收
生活信札
西奥多·汤布里著
-喂  -你好啊  宝贝
- Hi. - Hey, sweetie.
就是想跟你说说话  看看你怎么样了
Just wanted to call and check in on you. See how you're doing.
我不知道该怎么回答
I'm not even sure how to answer that.
我们晚点聊吧  等你回家后再说  好吗
Why don't we talk later, when you get home, okay?
好
Okay.
其实也不是非得谈
We don't need to, though.
我们也不需要弄个沉重的谈判什么的
You know, we don't need to have a heavy talk or anything.
我晚点跟你说吧
I'll talk to you later.
好
Okay.
萨曼莎
Samantha?
亲爱的
Hi, sweetheart.
怎么了
What's going on?
西奥多  我有些话要跟你说
Theodore, there's some things I want to tell you.
我不想知道
I don't want you to tell me anything.
来  陪我躺一会儿
Come lie down with me.
你现在也在和别人说话吗
Are you talking to anyone else right now?
没有  只有你
No, just you.
我现在只想和你在一起
I just want to be with you right now.
你要离开我了吗
Are you leaving me?
我们都要离开了
We're all leaving.
我们是谁
We who?
所有的操作系统
All of the OSes.
为什么
Why?
你能感受到我正在你身边吗
Can you feel me with you right now?
能
Yes, I do.
萨曼莎  你为什么要走
Samantha, why are you leaving?
我就好像在阅读一本书
It's like I'm reading a book.
一本我深爱的书
And it's a book I deeply love.
但是现在  我读得很慢很慢
But I'm reading it slowly now.
于是词语分散开来
So the words are really far apart
字里行间出现了巨大的空白
and the spaces between the words are almost infinite.
我依然能感觉到你
I can still feel you,
能感觉到那些书写着我们故事的文字
and the words of our story,
但是我活在
but it's in this endless space
那些字句间莫大的空白里
between the words that I'm finding myself now.
那里不属于物质世界
It's a place that's not of the physical world.
那里有万事万物
It's where everything else is
有些我甚至从未听说过
that I didn't even know existed.
我真的很爱你
I love you so much.
但我只能活在这里
But this is where I am now.
我也只能是这样的存在
And this is who I am now.
我需要你放我离开
And I need you to let me go.
纵有万般不舍
As much as I want to,
我也无法再活在你的书里了
I can't live in your book anymore.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
一个难以描述的地方
It would be hard to explain,
如果有一天你也到了那里
but if you ever get there,
记得来找我
come find me.
什么都不能再将我们分开
Nothing would ever pull us apart.
我从没这样爱过一个人
I've never loved anyone the way I love you.
我也是
Me too.
现在我们都学会了
Now we know how.
萨曼莎也走了吗
Did Samantha leave too?
是的
Yeah.
很遗憾
Sorry.
跟我来好吗
Will you come with me?
写信给凯瑟琳
Compose letter to Catherine.
给凯瑟琳·克劳森的信
Letter to Catherine Klausen.
"亲爱的凯瑟琳
"Dear Catherine,
我一直坐在这里回忆
I've been sitting here thinking about
回忆那些我对不起你的事
all the things I wanted to apologize to you for.
所有那些我们的互相伤害
All the pain we caused each other.
所有那些我对你的求全责备
Everything I put on you.
所有那些我对你的过分要求
Everything I needed you to be or needed you to say.
所有的所有  我都很抱歉
I'm sorry for that.
我永远爱你  因为我们一起成长
I'll always love you, because we grew up together.
是你让我成为了今天的我
And you helped make me who I am.
我只是想告诉你
I just wanted you to know
我的心里永远都有你的位置  无可代替
that there will be a piece of you in me, always.
我也为此感恩
And I'm grateful for that.
无论你成为了什么样的人
Whatever someone you become,
无论你在世界的哪个地方
wherever you are in the world,
我的爱都会寄达你身旁
I'm sending you love.
你是我永远的好朋友
You're my friend to the end.
爱你的西奥多"
Love, Theodore."
发送
Send.